PAUL: Alright, hello everyone, am I audible? Please let me know in the chats.
PAUL: Alright, Kiran is telling Notion is not getting updated, it's the same GitHub repo that previously we have shared.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Please check, I am audible or not.
PAUL: Everyone… Audible, audible? Okay, alright. Yes, I am running.
PAUL: So now you check your mic.
PAUL: Yogesh…
PAUL: Notion… okay, let me check the Notion, yes, that part I have not updated yet, because it's the same GitHub report.
PAUL: So, let me just start sharing my screen.
PAUL: So, this is desktop 3.
PAUL: Alright, now coming to Notion.
PAUL: Choose… okay.
PAUL: Alright, this part I have not updated, but I hope everyone understands, okay, the repo was the same, I will update it today after the class, because the actual GitHub link is the same that we have been discussing.
PAUL: Okay, so for anyone, you can directly refer to the last one, because it's exactly the same repo we have been discussing for the past, I think. Last week also.
PAUL: All right, so today's agenda, so let me just open… rag.md file… Perfect.
PAUL: Yeah, so…
PAUL: So, previously, we have gone through the data parses part, okay? Now, we'll be looking into, the first project. Okay, the project is a simple one, really. The idea is to get familiar with the entire ecosystem. It's not only about the RAG.
PAUL: For sure, today we'll be working on the fast API part, and probably, I think, next to next week, it will be about much more deployment. So today, nothing deployment, we will try to build everything from scratch.
PAUL: And I think in the last class, you guys have already done the setup of the environment, as well as…
PAUL: the, I think… environment and as well as your environment variables. Both the things you…
PAUL: have done it, please let me know with a yes or no in the last class.
PAUL: Notion notes, there is nothing. Notion, it's simply the same GitHub link Satish Kotha, okay? So that's all. Alright, fine. Now, I have added one template file today in the repo, so simply you can look into the template created.py file.
PAUL: So, just wait, I will add today's part here for now, and later, that part I will be adding.
PAUL: Mmm… 13…
PAUL: Okay, 14 December.
PAUL: wrote a cheat.
PAUL: They don't.
PAUL: First of all, let me add the GitHub link here.
PAUL: the GitHub link, do I have this with me?
PAUL: For newcomers, I'm just adding.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: writing my tree is… He changed.
PAUL: Alright, I have added the GitHub link here, so directly you can take the reference.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just get the browser.
PAUL: Alright, now, here you have one file, the template creator, okay? Now, using this few, the folder structure, that will be generated, but at least the things that we'll be discussing today, based on that.
PAUL: Now, Vardhan, if you're getting error, please don't tell me now, okay? After the class, you can let me know.
PAUL: Alright, so the first thing, let's…
PAUL: Talk a little bit about the project, exactly what we are going to do.
PAUL: Whoa.
PAUL: I think I have my FastAPI RagPy.
PAUL: Alert. Now…
PAUL: This will be the main application flow, okay, that we will try to build. Okay, so let me just zoom into each of the components.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: So, today, with respect to the framework, I think everybody has gone through the GitHub that I have provided. Okay, so a little bit. With respect to the overview, simply, the core idea will be building a simple rack using Landshin.
PAUL: And for evaluation, we have used metrics, so the entire tech stack, please do check it from here. Okay, language, API framework, rack framework, vector DB, embeddings, LLM, evaluation, observability, container, cloud, and finally, CIC.
PAUL: Okay, now these are all the components. Now, every component we will be working today, today will be the core RAG application part, because till now, we have only worked with Jupyter notebooks. And from today, like, majorly, like, with respect to projects, it will be modular coding. So, we'll be working with Python scripts a lot.
PAUL: So, first of all, we'll be building that fast API application. Once the application is built, and everything is working, we will do the testing with respect to containerization. Once containerization is done, then we will be talking about deployment. So, deployment pretty much next week, okay?
PAUL: So for now, in this particular project, we will just try to build the core RAG application, okay? And I think for that, I have close to 6 to 7 scripts, and a few similar setups that we'll be doing.
PAUL: So, first of all, let me start working on the project. Okay, first of all, I will just create a blank folder.
PAUL: Let me just get my terminal.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Please let me know if everything is visible or not.
PAUL: 13 dollars.
PAUL: Now, first of all, I will create a directory, a blank directory. Okay, and for this, I will give the name rag.
PAUL: Not sure.
PAUL: We can also randomly following this.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: I have created the project, then I will go inside the project.
PAUL: Do you guys want to follow me? Yes, you can follow, but just be sure, because you have the core GitHub, so I'm starting everything from scratch right now.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, you can start from scratch if you want to follow.
PAUL: How many people are following? You can let me know in the chat.
PAUL: Because if you are following,
PAUL: Then, really, like, from scratch, it will take time. How many are following?
PAUL: Alright, fine. Few people, like, 15 to 20 people are following, fine. Create a blank directory, go inside that directory. Now the next step is.
PAUL: Once I'm inside the directory, I'll be creating the virtual environment.
PAUL: Okay, so… Some basic setup for every project that we have done till Perfect. So, UV?
PAUL: VNV, okay?
PAUL: this one.
PAUL: Alright, now let me activate the environment.
PAUL: Now, once I have done the activation of the environment in the next step, what I need? I need,
PAUL: the, package installation part, okay? So packages are already available, so let me just open my code editor.
PAUL: Alright, so now I don't have any requirement.txt file. So, first of all, let me create a requirement.
PAUL: And, all this information I have already shared, okay, in the GitHub, you can directly copy-paste it. So what I will do, I will just go to my GitHub.
PAUL: And I will go to my requirement.txt file.
PAUL: Okay, don't use the dev version.
PAUL: For now, only use the simple one. So, let me get the raw one.
PAUL: Okay, so I've just pasted my requirements here.
PAUL: And I'm very specific, only two packages. One is the Raga's one, and the other one is Langsmith. Other than that, if you look, I don't think there is any other version mentioned. So just be sure.
PAUL: Okay, so in two places, because in Raga's latest 3.9, I was facing some issues, just like in class also I've discussed, so I'm using 3.7. Langsmith, you can keep it without the version as well as with the version.
PAUL: Perfect. Now, with the packages.
PAUL: Let's go through the packages. So, FastAPI, UVCon, this is our main…
PAUL: I can say framework for building the APIs. Then I do have Python multi-part, few packages with respect to LandChain, Quadrant client.
PAUL: for PDF, so right now, I think majorly the supports…
PAUL: are with PDF files for now that I have done. Then come your Pylic package, okay, because I'll be using some response models and query models, okay, where I'll be defining them for data validation, very specifically, like, for every API, for every route.
PAUL: Like, what will be the input, and what will be the output. For that, I have this one, and even for setting our configuration, I will be creating a file. Okay, so don't worry, there I'll be using Pydentity.
PAUL: Now, structured log, and finally, to make some HTTP calls, I'm using the package HTTPX. What is the purpose of using datasets?
PAUL: This particular baggage. Any voting remembers?
PAUL: During the notebooks, why we have used datasets.
PAUL: to create our evaluation data set in RAGAS, if you remember. Okay?
PAUL: Now, finally, comes your ADAS package, alright? So, majorly, all the things are there.
PAUL: So, first of all, let me do the installation of all the packages.fnr requirement.txt, okay? So, right now.
PAUL: I can say immediately all the installation of the packages are done.
PAUL: Now, I can start building the framework.
PAUL: requirements, okay, in the chat, I can see somebody is asking for, please share the packages. Please go to GitHub. From GitHub, I have taken… you have to also take from GitHub further.
PAUL: Okay, hugging Face dataset, okay, evaluation, fine, I've already done the BNB and the API part. Alright, great.
PAUL: Now, there is one file that I have, which is basically the template creator file.
PAUL: So, let me take that file. Where is GitHub? Okay, alright.
PAUL: Because creating one one folder… okay, so… later on we can create, but at least few folders, I feel that.
PAUL: we need it.
PAUL: Initially.
PAUL: Okay, because the root… project directory that I have.
PAUL: This might create an issue.
PAUL: Hmm… alright, fine.
PAUL: The right human.
PAUL: Alright, let me just take this entire script for now.
PAUL: Without taking the script, also, I can do… please let me know, do you want me to execute the script or create folder manually? Whichever way you guys are comfortable, I can do that. Please let me know, because we are in one-shot everything, manually.
PAUL: or script.
PAUL: Few people are telling, do it manually, some people script, okay?
PAUL: You see, people were telling manually to mean that, really, like, you have to understand Python scripts.
PAUL: Because one by one, let's start creating then. Nothing that I can do. Few people are telling, do it manually. In the first project, I'm doing it manually. Going forward, in every project, I will be using scripts.
PAUL: Alright, so let me just, just minimize every stop here.
PAUL: We were looking at this… this part… I don't mute.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: around Notion point.
PAUL: Where is my bus? Okay.
PAUL: Let's start create, so VNB is available.
PAUL: Okay, not within the VA and B.
PAUL: I need a .env file.
PAUL: ANV file is important. Now, I will start creating the folders. So, the first folder that I'll be creating, which is basically the app folder, APT.
PAUL: Okay, so inside this app, everything will be there. Okay.
PAUL: So, the app folder, within that app folder, I'll be creating the structure. So, first of all, with respect to our frameworks that I'll be discussing. Okay, the fast API part.
PAUL: So, let me just add another folder inside this, which is my API.
PAUL: Mmm… I think slash routes.
PAUL: You guys can refer to the script, because right now I'm doing it automatically, okay, because I know what will be the exact folder structure that I will be using, but you can look into the script.
PAUL: Alright, now, app part I have done.
PAUL: Shen, you have that show folder this way?
PAUL: Alright. Now, within the app, the first folder is only for the API part. Now, the next folder will be the main one, which is the core.
PAUL: Okay, so I think… okay, sorry, I'm creating a file, I need a folder.
PAUL: the core folder. Now, this core folder will be your main folder where every logic with respect to your RAM will be available.
PAUL: So, in this entire thing, okay, the core folder will be the main responsible folder. Here, I'll be keeping all my scripts with respect to embeddings, okay, with respect to document processing.
PAUL: with respect to, building our final, rack chain, so all the core modules, I'll be keeping it here.
PAUL: Nagra is telling too fast how you created that. Please, guys, let me know that. Is it fast?
PAUL: I'm just creating folders now.
PAUL: really, like, I have not started writing code, I've just created the folder.
PAUL: And step by step, I'm doing everything.
PAUL: Now, for the ENB part, A and B part variables, you can directly get it from GitHub.
PAUL: Okay, so you can look into that, .env.example.
PAUL: Okay, so let's take everything from here.
PAUL: Popular raw file.
PAUL: Okay? Now, in this environment file, so one is the OpenAI API key that I have.
PAUL: Then comes the quadrant URL, so everything is configured for me. Okay, I will do a simple copy-paste, but then the collection name, it means that within our quadrant cluster, exactly what will be the name of that collection that I'll be creating. For now, there is a single collection, and within that collection, I'll be adding the documents.
PAUL: Then in the next step, chunk size and chunk overlap.
PAUL: Okay, then few settings with respect to using the LLM, the LLM temperature, the embedding model. Now, a few things, you can keep it in configuration file also, which I'll be creating soon, but these are few settings, because at every point of time, I don't want to go inside the code and change anything, if I want to experiment also. But directly from the ENV file also, I can do the changes.
PAUL: Then here, the top.
PAUL: K chunks, so for that, retrieval underscore K.
PAUL: is the main variable that I am using. Then I'll be creating a simple logger using Python. So, for that, the idea is to log all the info-level, logs.
PAUL: I'm not looking into the other debug and others. Okay, if you want, you can do that. Then for Fast API, I have… so this is my localhost settings. So, localhost 8000, I know my FastAPI server will run in this particular port.
PAUL: And then finally comes your Langsmith settings. Okay, so Landsmith settings today, it's not required, but at least I feel that till this point, everything should be configured in your system.
PAUL: Now, let me just take all the information.
PAUL: Temperature zero, we, prefer. The idea is to get deterministic weather in the sun.
PAUL: And 0 is much preferred, 0.3 we don't use a lot.
PAUL: Alright, so let me just get my ENV.
PAUL: Okay, and I think everybody has configured this part.
PAUL: Okay, so… My ANB configuration is done, okay? Now, the same idea that you people have done the configuration. Please let me know. ANB part is done. For me, also, this is done. Yesterday, I already told.
PAUL: No?
PAUL: the core application part, I will start working.
PAUL: SK is asking, what is logging? In any programming language, logging is a common standard. During production, you always look into the logs.
PAUL: Whatever, operations that are going in specifically that you want to log based on date and time, you have to do that.
PAUL: Because logging is a concept which is used in Python.
PAUL: Really.
PAUL: somebody is telling, please show the ENV file. ENV file, please check your GitHub. I think somewhere in the GitHub I've kept it. Okay, so here you'll be getting it.
PAUL: please refer to the official GitHub repo. Immediately, I'll be picking up. You can open this, take a clone, open it, and in some ID, so that you can quickly do a copy-paste. Otherwise, I am doing it from the official GitHub repo, so that you guys can follow.
PAUL: whatever is there inside this particular ENV file, you have to just pass that, as simple as that. Don't get confused.
PAUL: Alright, even in the last class, I have told you to do this.
PAUL: Right now, everything, I'm doing it in my local SK.
PAUL: And it's not necessary. Right now, I'm just using the log. I'm not saving the log. Later on, for logs in project 2 or 3, I'll be talking about
PAUL: better frameworks, like Log Guru.
PAUL: But for now, I've just taken a simple implementation with Python.
PAUL: Kindly confirm the LLM model and the embedding model should be same. Akhil, how can you ask me the question? Such questions right now…
PAUL: Just think, LLM model and embedding model, how they can be the same.
PAUL: Booth has different purpose.
PAUL: Embedding model, I think, text embedding 3 small data I'm using.
PAUL: Okay, and the LLM, I'm using GPT4 Mini. You can change it to GPT 5.1, 5 Nano, anything.
PAUL: Langsmith Key, yesterday I have already told. Yesterday, yes, quadrant part also done.
PAUL: from the same vendor ID.
PAUL: It's totally up to you, I have no issues if you want to use some other embedding model. Okay, totally your choice. Gemini, if you are going to work with Gemini, so later on, during the
PAUL: changes in the code, I'll be talking about that. But please let me know, because till now I've not started coding yet. I'm just doing some basic configuration.
PAUL: So, this part is important that, yes, everybody has followed till this part.
PAUL: Then I will move to the next part.
PAUL: Hardik Karna is telling, please, please, regarding what Hardik?
PAUL: Milint Kurkan is telling, I can't find the ENV file in GitHub. Milint, I have shared the .env.example file. Nobody shares .env file in GitHub.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: Now, this part is done. Okay, now moving to the core part.
PAUL: So, see, in the data, right now, I am going inside the app folder, because this is the folder that majorly today will be working with. So, the first thing, if you look into the structure, the API, the core, and the utils. Okay, so let me just create another folder, the utility folder, where I'll be keeping my logger implementation.
PAUL: Okay, because before starting the project, these are a few things that needs to be taken care of.
PAUL: Okay, so here I will create my utils.
PAUL: Okay, and inside the utils…
PAUL: I'll be keeping my logger, so let me just show you the implementation of logger that I have done. It's pretty much pure Python, I'm not using any fancy library for now.
PAUL: So, here, logging input sales from func tools, I've taken LRU catcher. So, generally, in RAT pipelines, LRU catcher is pretty much helpful. If you're executing any type of expensive functions, then directly from the catcher gets picked up.
PAUL: Okay? But for local implementation only, not for production. Now, here, I am setting. So, right now, I'm configuring my logs. Okay, so please…
PAUL: Look into this part, let me just collapse this.
PAUL: I want you to look into this script, because this script for every project, there's things everybody learns in Python. This is nothing related to this project.
PAUL: So, right now, for the logging setup, I am using the core logging module from Python, and based on that, this is my main formatter. So, based on this particular format, I need my logs.
PAUL: Okay, so once I have configured my formatter, now in the next step, the idea is to apply, and a few noise-related libraries. Okay, so HTTPS, HTTP core. For these type of libraries, we do get a lot of warnings, so simply, I want to ignore those warnings.
PAUL: So I'm simply setting up the logger here.
PAUL: Now, finally, applying the logger, so this will be the main function with respect to where I'm applying catching, so def, get logger, okay, logging.logger.
PAUL: And then finally, the logger mixing class.
PAUL: Okay, so mixing class to add logging capability to directly any type of Python classes on top of which I want to apply this logger, I can directly call the logger, and automatically my logging will be, applied. So this is a simple module part.
PAUL: Okay, now, this is nothing related to ragged, simple, pure Python implementation.
PAUL: Yay, are you catch it for local. So, generally, in rack pipelines, just think about the same query if I'm executing 10 times, so somehow it helps in execution faster, that's why.
PAUL: Generally, for expensive functions, if I'm making repeated calls in that case, LRU Catcher is helpful. Only for local implementation, not for production.
PAUL: Alright, now, this… within the utils, I have my logger. So, let me just take the logger implementation from here, and I will create a file, logger.py.
PAUL: First of all, I will just create init also.
PAUL: Everywhere you have…
PAUL: Logger. In every project, we'll be working with loggers.
PAUL: Okay, and here I will paste the script.
PAUL: Hold it.
PAUL: So, the first part with respect to the logger implementation, you can keep the logger implementation much more simpler also.
PAUL: Because this is… what?
PAUL: That finally came, so console logger. This is the main, stream handler. Like, in terminal, you'll be getting all your results.
PAUL: Alright, now with respect to the logger part.
PAUL: Hardin was telling I'm new to Project 2M. I'll ask these questions during the doubts.
PAUL: If you are new, nothing that I can do, okay, I can let you know after when I start taking troubles.
PAUL: For production, what is recommended? You'll be using some production-grade logging system.
PAUL: Yes, I'm using Corset today.
PAUL: Please let me know, everybody has done the… Configuration of the logger.
PAUL: Can I proceed ahead?
PAUL: Naga is asking, app folder, how you create it? Just, you can create it using MKTI, or manually from the UI, also, you can create.
PAUL: Creating folders, really, I cannot teach you how to create folders by this time in this course.
PAUL: Okay, so the utils part is done.
PAUL: Okay, now… the API routes, okay. Now, the next thing, let's start working on the config file.
PAUL: Okay, because for configuration settings, I have… and most of the times, everybody uses a config, so directly from the config, you can change, it's a better practice, rather than everything, you don't want to pass it within the environment we need. So, for example, few things here that I feel that it will be better if
PAUL: if I can keep them in a configuration setting, because really, these things…
PAUL: Can be helpful sometimes, but I feel in configuration they will be better. Now, with respect to the config, implementation.
PAUL: Taurabh is asking why we are not using notebook type of implementation.
PAUL: Really, sort of… Then, why we are doing the project.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Let me go into… API.
PAUL: Okay, and inside this routes, I'll be talking about this route later on, when we will start working on the FastAPI app. The initial idea is basically, first to work on the LangChain part. Okay, once the LangChain app is working, then we will do the integration with FastAPI.
PAUL: So, let me get my config file, I think.
PAUL: directly within API, I can create it.
PAUL: Okay, so let me show you where is my config file that I have. So directly, you can see it is within the app folder, and if you open this folder, config.py.
PAUL: Okay, now this is my main config that I have. So, please look into here. So, from Functus, I'm inputting LRU catcher.
PAUL: from Pydentic settings, I am importing the base settings and the settings content. Okay, so this is… the idea is to do data validation.
PAUL: And exactly the things that I'm… so right now, within this base setting from Pydentic, okay, so right now, settings configured, I have passed my ENV file. It means that, whenever this, particular, I can say, settings will be loaded, because most of the times we'll be loading these settings.
PAUL: So in this, during that time, automatically your ENV file will also come into the picture.
PAUL: And other than that, I have defined few…
PAUL: data types. Like, for OpenAI, the key, it will be string. For quadrant URL, it will be string. Quadrant API key, it will be string. Collection name, again string. Chunk size, integer, this time I've changed the data type. Similarly, for embedding model, again string. LLM model, again string. Okay, LLM temperature, you can see here, float.
PAUL: Okay, then comes your retrieval K, here again, int, log level, info. So, majorly, see, if you look here, I have only defined the data types that I require.
PAUL: Look till logging, at least, because this part is important.
PAUL: Everybody. Because this is the use of, using PyDactic.
PAUL: I don't think why it become famous? Just because it's a data validation framework. So right now, I'm doing data validation.
PAUL: Now, somebody's asking why it is necessary to define data type if we are using Python.
PAUL: Really, guys, see, you have to focus on the basics of Python. If somebody passed something else here, rather than an int, if somebody passed a character, then what will happen?
PAUL: The idea is to do the restriction in the initial level. That is the purpose of Identec.
PAUL: Because I know few people with lesser,
PAUL: like, I can say, who don't have good Python foundations, it can be a problem.
PAUL: So, what is the purpose? The idea is that I'm doing the data validation in this step only, because if I pass any parameters later on, I know that simply it will throw an error, a data type error, using PyDentic.
PAUL: Okay? Till now, I've not executed anything, Mantas, so how you can get an error at compile time?
PAUL: please let me know, everyone with respect to the config, what I have done. Now, this is the main config file, the config.py, where I have done the data validation. Similarly, for other metrics also, because we will be adding the evaluation part, so for that, I'm enabling Raga's evaluation boolean, so by default, I'm keeping it true.
PAUL: Okay, from here, directly, you can make it false, so during
PAUL: The prediction part, or basically, when you are making the query, by default, if you change this setting from true to false, true means evaluation will be done, false means evaluation won't be done.
PAUL: Then Raga's timeout second, so this I have taken, like, minimum as, like, 30.0.
PAUL: Then comes Raga log results. Again, Boolean. Okay, I need the log results, so there I'll be using the logger. Then comes what will be your evaluation model.
PAUL: Okay, what will be the evaluation LLM?
PAUL: Then, what will be your RAGAS, evaluation LLM temperature, and what will be the embedding model for RAGAS? Now, these are only for RAGAS evaluation that I have done.
PAUL: Okay, so these are only the configurations in every project you create. Sometimes… have you guys worked with config.yml? YML files?
PAUL: Because right now, I'm using Python, but majorly in production, we use YML files. We don't use config.py, because going forward, I will change the structure, but the idea is that, let's start with something, because directly if I bring, like, people are asking questions, so…
PAUL: Let's start with something easy. You may use XML, no.
PAUL: XML is not my preference. I prefer much more YML or simple PY.
PAUL: Alright, then finally comes your API settings.
PAUL: Okay, so these are for FastAPI that I have.
PAUL: Then, application info.
PAUL: Okay, so… now, this application info, why I've kept it? So, like, when you open your local host directly, the root version in slash, you'll be getting this application info. So, when we'll be working with FastAP, so this is much related to FastAPI settings.
PAUL: So, whenever you look into the term application or API, it means that I'm referring to the Fast API framework.
PAUL: Okay, and then, finally applying LRU catcher on top of the entire settings, so, like, I know that most of the things will get captured, so I will get faster execution.
PAUL: Now, all these settings, you don't change every time, so I'm using the catch. If you feel that you change at every run, then using the catch really, like, it is of no such use.
PAUL: What do you mean by settings?
PAUL: So, generally, whenever we do the config settings for any type of project, we refer to as the settings, because if you look into, I'm, inheriting, or basically, I'm using the base settings from PythNTIC, and using that, I'm doing the validation, so we are referring the term settings here.
PAUL: Could you explain what, application does and the purpose of the application? I will come to that. First of all, let's start with the basic settings part. Till now, I've not started coding for Lansion. When I start doing it for Lansion, then I will come to that part.
PAUL: Somebody's asking what is the purpose of underscore, underscore init underscore underscore py. Pramesh, first, please focus on Python.
PAUL: How many of you know about this underscore, underscore Python?
PAUL: Really, these are simple Pythonic concepts. It means that whenever you are working with respect to modules, you need to do that. These are standards.
PAUL: most of you need to focus on your Python I feel.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Hmm, alright, fine. Now… Let's get back.
PAUL: To our app, okay, because the config.
PAUL: I think myconfig.py within the app, on fig.ty.
PAUL: I've added the config, okay, now I will pass the information directly here.
PAUL: Alright, so config part is done.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, so for everybody, I think, the config part you have done, and please do follow the structure that I have used it here. If you want the reference with respect to structure, okay, please go and look into the README file, at least in the README file. I think… have I kept the structure?
PAUL: If not, okay, now, this is where we'll get the project structure, within your README file. So, from here, you will have a good idea. So, directly, you can look into this structure. So, for exactly where is my
PAUL: Config, so directly till under app.
PAUL: Okay? So please do refer this particular structure, or directly you can open the folder here also, and based on that, the structure that, we are using.
PAUL: PyDentic is used for agent creation, no, pygenting. It is used, but the core purpose of using Pydentic UNAS, it is for data validation.
PAUL: Yes, correct.
PAUL: Alright. Now, let's come and let's look into exactly, what are the main core parts of the application that we are working on.
PAUL: So, initially, within the app, we had 3 modules, if you remember, 3 modules, okay? One module was the utils module, so where, very specifically, I have kept logger implementation, so this is that part.
PAUL: Now, with respect to the API call, it means that anything, if I ask, so how it will work? It means that you have an interface, in that interface, you will be asking some type of question, a query to the app.
PAUL: So generally, in that case, what happens? So, first of all, whatever that request, it will come to the Fast API server, okay, and that entry point of your application is app slash mean.py.
PAUL: This is the entry point. It means that your application starts from this file.
PAUL: it means that you will be executing this file to, execute this entire application, or this particular project. So this file is your main entry point.
PAUL: I hope everybody understands entry point.
PAUL: With respect to applications.
PAUL: any programming language. Okay, it means that from this particular point only, your application will start. This is the first file which will get loaded during the execution, like index.js, yes.
PAUL: Okay, now here, if you look into… now, in this file, there are a lot of implementations with respect to
PAUL: I can say FastAPI. Okay, now, the idea is that, okay, my request will come to my API framework, which is FastAPI, then I have course middleware. So, generally, what is the purpose of using CORS?
PAUL: C-U-R-F?
PAUL: Anywhere.
PAUL: like, domains, yes. Like, if you have multiple servers, okay, in that case, if you are not using cores, you might get an error. Ross domain access. Okay, if it is in the same server, then generally it doesn't happen, but if the servers are totally different, okay, in that case, yes, it can create a problem.
PAUL: Now, a few basic routes that I have within this FastAPI. Okay, means each route is responsible. First of all, I do have a health route, okay? This slash health, health.py. Now, this is very specific to FastAPI, just to check that the application is up and working.
PAUL: Then I have my slash documents. Okay, now…
PAUL: The idea is that you will be injecting some type of document
PAUL: It means that you can upload your document, and based on that, the processing will take place, the data ingestion phase, if I'm talking about. So that is within this document.py that we'll be talking about. So I have one route which will check, okay, the application is up and working, which is slash L, then I have my API routes, the slash documents, okay, where your data ingestion phase will take place, it means that it will upload some PDF,
PAUL: then that PDF, like, the process of,
PAUL: parsing, chunking, adding the embedding to quadrant, so all those things, step by step, that will take place. And finally, once the data ingestion phase is done, then comes your second phase, where you'll be asking the query.
PAUL: Okay, so that's, like, 3 simple routes, slash health, slash document, slash query.
PAUL: Okay, that we have. One to ask the question, one to inject the document, one to check the status of the application. Is this part clear with respect to the API route?
PAUL: Alright, now this part is done. Now see, based on 3 routes, okay, now I will come to my core services.
PAUL: Okay, so with respect to poor services, so if you really look into… So, first of all, the slash health. So, right now, the slash health is basically checking for a lot of service, like the vector store service. Vector store
PAUL: service means that it is connected with some type of, vectored DB database. It means that the connection is perfect and there is no issues. It means that you have passed the correct quadrant URL, you have passed the correct API key.
PAUL: Okay? So here, this is the vector store service, and what is the purpose of this service? If you inject any document.
PAUL: parsing, chunking, and then the embeddings will be done. Once the embeddings are done, okay, then the next step is basically using this vector store service, which will upload your embeddings to Quadrant Cloud.
PAUL: Right now, in this particular project, we are not using local quadrant. We have taken a cloud cluster, okay? So, all your embeddings that you have created using your embedding model, those will be pushed.
PAUL: So now, this vector store is connected with our embeddings.py.
PAUL: Okay, so for sure, it has to be connected. Then, embeddings.py, if you really look into. So now, coming to the part with respect to document processing, because the next thing is, with respect to documents, where you upload a document, there is a document processor.py file, which is responsible to do your document processing. In document processing, what you do? You will perform in some type of parsing.
PAUL: After the parsing, you'll be applying some type of chunking, okay? So, here, that's why the chunk
PAUL: Metrics that we have with respect to text splitting.
PAUL: mechanism that we have used, recursive character text splitter, chunk size 1000 overlap. Okay, now this is the core document service. Other than that, I don't think there should be anything in the document service. Because once your chunking is done, what is the next step?
PAUL: To move towards the embedding part, and then finally coming to your vector store.
PAUL: Okay?
PAUL: Now, during the query, okay, so you can see, here, during the help, the directory will go to the vector operations, and based on that, it will have a check that, okay, everything is up or not. For document processing, okay, so one route is going directly towards the vector service.
PAUL: It means that for vectorized operation, which is required, and the other one is for document processing.
PAUL: Now, finally, coming to the query part. In query, what I have done, I have divided the query into two parts.
PAUL: Okay, like, there are a few parameters and arguments. It means that if you want evaluation, then only we'll be doing them. It's an optional thing. Okay, so right now, during the query, what happens? So, can you see this flow? Inside this flow, can I say that, yes, if the query comes, I have to convert it into embeddings first.
PAUL: Yes or no. Once you get the query, you have to convert them into embeddings, so that's why this particular line is going there.
PAUL: Okay, now from embeddings, basically, it will first reach the vector store service, from the vector store service to the embedding service. Now, from the embedding service to that specific embedding model, the final call will go.
PAUL: Yes, this is mandatory. Yes, this is mandatory. Like, every point of time, you do need it.
PAUL: Okay, now this process, once you have the embeddings, then only you can perform a query, okay? Because, now, once you have this embeddings, then again, this vector store service, the call will go to this, okay, and then we will be looking into the documents.
PAUL: Now, this… that's why this phase that comes. Now, the other phase that I have, okay, where you'll be invoking that entire rag, it means that once your embeddings are ready, can I say that I can invoke my rag chain?
PAUL: Because inside your RAM chain, you'll be passing, all those things, like prompt will come, LLM will come, string output parser that can come.
PAUL: Okay, all those type of… then that helper format function that we have discussed, that will come. So everything is available within the chain. It means that once the embeddings are ready, so we know that we can do the query. So that's why this particular chain will be evaluated.
PAUL: Now, within this chain, you can see the rack prompt template that is mentioned, but other things are not mentioned here.
PAUL: Now, then comes the Ragas evaluator. Now, this is optional that I have kept it. It means that
PAUL: During your inferencing, there is a parameter of true and false. If you feel that, okay, for this particular query, I need an evaluation, you can make it true. If you feel that you don't need the evaluation, it will be false. So, for every query, I am doing it.
PAUL: Is this part clear? Can we see the same architecture somewhere? It's very informative and easy to understand.
PAUL: Yes, yes, I will. If I have done it, okay, I will share, don't worry.
PAUL: this particular diagram. But this is the main core service that I have. Okay. Now, this service that I'll be building, all these core services right now, then I will come to the part, this blue color. So, first of all, we need to start working on this yellow color block.
PAUL: And this red color. Red color is much more about configuration directly. Okay, but this is the core service, so if you really look into, I need to work on the vector store service.
PAUL: The embedding service, the document processor, the rag chain, the RAG evaluator. Okay, so 1, 2, 3, 4, 5. Majority, I have 5 files that I need to start working on.
PAUL: Is this part clear? Exactly. What is the process? Can you explain why document is connected to Vector Store? Really, like, if somebody's asking this question.
PAUL: Because at the end of the day, all your documents will go to Vector Store, so Bash.
PAUL: Okay. RAG evaluator, I have kept it as an optional one, so directly through arguments and parameters that we can do.
PAUL: After query conversion, yes, it will go to the embedding. So, see, actually, this is the main service, the vector store service, where any type of things that can be initialized.
PAUL: Like, it has a direct reference with embeddings.py.
PAUL: Please let me know if this part clear, then only we can start the coding part.
PAUL: Because we will be working on this core part, where we have multiple
PAUL: files, and these files that we'll be creating, vector underscore store, embeddings, rag chain, document processor, rag evaluator, okay, and finally the template that we have.
PAUL: Somebody is selling text splitter is not connected with Vector Store.
PAUL: like, direct… like, if you think about it, yes, directly I have not added, but I hope you get the idea, because, see, at the end of the day, the text bitter is connected with document processor. This is the main one. Now, the document processor has to be connected with vectors, too.
PAUL: Always think in class level, not in function level.
PAUL: Alec.
PAUL: So, I'm going to repeat myself. Okay, please follow from the starting point. Okay, now the idea is that we do have some type of application. Now, somebody is raising some type of request, okay? So, before the request, let's talk about the data ingestion phase. So, for data ingestion.
PAUL: What do you need? You need to upload some type of PDF or some type of document.
PAUL: Okay, so in the client layer, so through HTTP request, the first entry point is basically your fast API,
PAUL: application, which is the main.py. Once the request comes there, it will go through course middleware, and then finally, all my available routes, so 3 routes that I have, it will be used. First, to check the health of the application, then to do any type of data ingestion, so slash documents, so this is responsible to my data ingestion.
PAUL: And slash query is, basically to do any type of query operation once the data ingestion phase is done.
PAUL: So, 3 routes, 3 specific routes. So, directly, if you want to do any upload operation, you have to use this route.
PAUL: And if you want to perform a query, you get this out. Now, the first phase is data ingestion. So, generally, in data ingestion, what you do, okay, some type of file that will be uploaded, it will be coming to our main core service, which is the document
PAUL: processor. Now, inside this document processor, okay, it is connected with our text beta. So now, this one is actually connected with a vector store. It means that, okay, once our, chunks are available, those chunks will be converted into embeddings, and finally, they will be pushed into vector store.
PAUL: Okay, so this is the entire flow from here to here. Now, once your data ingestion part is done, in the next step, the idea is to make some type of queries. So, for those type of queries, you can see the query first, the embedding will take place for the query. Once embedding is available, then the chain will be activated. Now, within that activation of the chain, so prompt template, it is a must one, and for the
PAUL: Optional one, I have kept the evaluator. It means that if you pass the parameter, then only the evaluation will take place, otherwise it won't take.
PAUL: Okay, and these are a few external services which my core services are connected with.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Can we proceed ahead with the coding part?
PAUL: But here, the query is directly related to the vector store. The query is not related to vector store, it is related to just the embedding service. The embedding service is connected with the vector store.
PAUL: Please get that.
PAUL: Always the mean block, that is the mean service, the vector store.
PAUL: Similarly, always look into this main chain, the document processor, the ratch, and the vector store. Don't try to directly compare with this one. The main block needs to be connected.
PAUL: All right, fine. Now let's focus on the part with respect to the code part. Now I will start a little bit working on core.
PAUL: Okay, so let's get back Okay?
PAUL: Okay, so now this core folder is pretty blank. First of all, let me just initialize with an init.py.
PAUL: And now…
PAUL: All the files I'll be creating in one shot. Okay, so all those files, the name were mentioned. So, document.
PAUL: processor.py. If I make a spelling mistake, please, let me know.
PAUL: sometimes I do make, mistakes.
PAUL: The Alright, now after the document processor is done, then probably I need embeddings.py.
PAUL: Alright, now, once the embeddings are done, then comes our vector underscore store.
PAUL: Once the vector store is done, okay, so then remaining, I do have a rag chain and a raggy band vector.
PAUL: Beautiful.
PAUL: And, drag. Evaluate.
PAUL: Okay, so these are the major 5 files. If you go here, if you look, 1, 2, 3, 4, okay, and 5. All those 5 files I have created now.
PAUL: Okay, which will be working around the core service.
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: Is this fine?
PAUL: I've just created blank files, nothing that I have added.
PAUL: All great.
PAUL: Yes, I will share the project after the class, don't worry.
PAUL: Ragas evaluator, okay, RAG evaluator, I've done, yes, thanks, stands for this. Let me know, sometimes I do miss it, it is ragas underscore evaluate, correct.
PAUL: Now, the first thing when you look into.
PAUL: Okay, so what is the most important part that we should start with?
PAUL: Let me know. When you look into it, because when you are building a rack, what is the first step?
PAUL: You need some type of data.
PAUL: Okay, and for that, we need some type of documents. So, we will start with the document processor part. Data ingestion, okay? So, based on that, so let's start working on the document processor. So, first of all, let's discuss exactly what's there in document processor.
PAUL: Okay, and how this is getting invoked also.
PAUL: So first of all, let me go to the API part once.
PAUL: route.
PAUL: Okay, now, the documents.py.
PAUL: Now, this is basically the fast API part. Okay, now, as I told you, the…
PAUL: API, or basically the API framework, fast API which I'm using, it will make the call to document processing. Okay, so now this is the main input.
PAUL: So, the idea is to show you that, okay, where I am calling, this is the first import for document processor. Okay, because going forward, then directly I can jump it here.
PAUL: Okay, and you can see this is the main class document processor, on top of which I'm building the file.
PAUL: Okay, so it means that right now, I'm not working on Fast API, but you have to understand, the Fast API will make the call to the document processor. Okay? Now, we will start working with the document processor. Similarly, the other service, the vector store service.
PAUL: Now, this file, directly, you can open it. This is our actual document processing, which will be doing the implementation.
PAUL: Now, here, if you, look into, okay, import diffs, file, pathlib, binary I.O, so pretty much common imports, and I think all the lanchain imports.
PAUL: you guys are comfortable with. There is nothing new, I think. Please let me know. These are the only three lineup inputs from LanChain. Other than that, the other, implementations are much more with respect to our core module.
PAUL: Please let me know, everybody is comfortable with this, the import section.
PAUL: Alright, so first of all, let me just take the import part.
PAUL: Okay? Step by step, I will just do a copy-paste, because if I start writing, okay, it will take a lot of time.
PAUL: Alright, so this is my document processor, and right now, as you can see here, nothing I have imported. Okay. Now the question comes, you need to initialize your logger. Okay, so right now, as you can see here, from app.config input get settings.
PAUL: Okay? So, right now, get settings, yes, I'm not using it anywhere. Then comes your GET logger. So, let me check once.
PAUL: that with respect to inputs, because, as you can see, automatically, it is suggesting I know that, yes, I do need this particular implementation.
PAUL: Okay, but I will be taking it directly from the script.
PAUL: Now, once I have done the inputs, in the next step, Let's get back here.
PAUL: Okay, like, I'll be initializing my logger, okay, because I have imported the logger, but you need to do the initialization of that. Now comes my class. So, within this class.
PAUL: I think everybody is familiar with Python classes. Okay, now, the main purpose of this class is basically to process documents for rack pipeline.
PAUL: And in docstring, simply, I have written that, okay, now these are the supported extensions, okay? So, within a date, very specifically, I'm maintaining that, okay, only these type of files will be accepted, so that's why this extension part that I have kept it.
PAUL: Now, the first comes defining your constructor, okay? So, or your init function in Python. Now, what are the parameters to this
PAUL: particular constructor. So, first is self.
PAUL: Chunk size, chunk overlap.
PAUL: Okay? Only 3 major things that we do have with respect to the params.
PAUL: Why we don't have document parsing?
PAUL: I'm doing the document parsing here.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so here, these are the main parameters. It means that to initialize my document processor class, one is chunk size and chunk overlap. These two are the main ones.
PAUL: Then, coming to within the constructor, what are the things that I have initialized? So, get settings.
PAUL: Now, if I pass something inside the constructor, or within your main in it, within the class, what is the meaning of that?
PAUL: Yes, what is the meaning of that in Python? If you keep something within the constructor, and if you call it.
PAUL: Loading time, yes, like, load it once.
PAUL: once your application gets… okay, now this will be the fixed value. So, simply, all these things will be loaded in one shot. That is the main purpose.
PAUL: Alright, now, so, similarly, okay, based on the params that I have, so self.chunk size, self.chunk overlap, okay, now see, here I have kept it chunk underscore size. Now, very specifically, if you pass it within the parameter.
PAUL: or settings.chunk. So, if you remember, I think somewhere within the settings file, also, I have kept the chunk.
PAUL: So… within the settings, so if I go back here… my config.
PAUL: Can you see here?
PAUL: That's why there is an OR condition. It means that if somebody is hard-coding it, otherwise it will be picked from there.
PAUL: So, both the options, that's why that OR is there.
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: Now, coming to your text splitter operation, which is basically the recursive character text splitter, and based on that, I am added some simple separators for now.
PAUL: Now, I'm initializing my logger, so, like, very specifically, so document processor initialized with chunk size, this one, and chunk overline. Now, this information will be available in your terminal. Now, this is info-level. Okay, so all those info-level information will be available directly in your terminal when I'll be calling it.
PAUL: Okay, so now let's take the first part of this one.
PAUL: Okay, so I think… We just use embedding Factor Store.
PAUL: Config, Ratching, drivers, evaluator, document processor.
PAUL: Now, let's bring this piece of code, our main class, with our logger.
PAUL: Is this part clear?
PAUL: exactly what is there in the document processor class. Till now, it is not complete. I have only discussed the constructor.
PAUL: But let me know, is this part clear for everyone?
PAUL: Amit is asking the use of recursive character splitter. I need some type of chunking strategy, so I've used that.
PAUL: Yes, if the chunk is none, then automatically from the settings it will be picked up, correct.
PAUL: Alright, the first part is done, okay? Now let's get back to the next part.
PAUL: Now, the idea is to load the PDF, so within this class, I have my…
PAUL: other functions. Okay, so which is loading the PDF.
PAUL: As simple as that, if you really look into only one important line which is important, this one. Loader, PDFloader, and documents is equal to loader.load. This will load my PDF. Yes, on them.
PAUL: Other than that, there is… this is docstring.
PAUL: Okay, these are my simple file paths, okay? And then, finally, I'm loading the document. It means that in whichever file path it will get the document, based on that, it will be loading the file. Okay, now this is a placeholder.
PAUL: Piper.
PAUL: Okay, which I can define later on. So right now, this is the simple boilerplate that I am building, so that you can inject any type of documents, and later on, we can change it.
PAUL: Alright, so let me get it. Right now, the loading function is pretty much simple and straightforward.
PAUL: No, I'm not using… I'm trying to keep everything simple for now.
PAUL: Alright, so the first one with respect to use.
PAUL: Alright, loading the PDF is done.
PAUL: Somebody is asking, it should be loading, and then parsing, and then chunking.
PAUL: So, right now, I've just done loading, and simply I have loaded. I have not applied any type of chunking right now.
PAUL: Is this part clear? Till now, I have just created a function which will load the file. Where have I applied chunky?
PAUL: Really, like… All right.
PAUL: So, similarly, for other file types, so this is, say, so this was for PDF, similarly, there is a text loader that I am used from LanChain, and similarly, I do have a CSV loader.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, now, every type of file, first of all, let me get these two PDFs done.
PAUL: I think… this TSAV, 3 things, let me get it.
PAUL: So, I'm just using different type of classes right now, just to load the stuff. Okay, so one…
PAUL: Loader is for PDF, the other one is for text, and the other one is for CSV. Three simple things, directly from Langchen, I've taken it. I'm not taking any type of parsing-based frameworks. You can change this particular point at any point of time.
PAUL: Okay, hold on.
PAUL: Okay, so simply now, this is a check with respect to the extensions, like Ninima, you asked. Are you doing any type of validation while loading the file? So, a simple validation that I have kept it with respect to this load.
PAUL: PIE function, which basically checks the extension.
PAUL: Okay? So, load a file based on its extension, and already I have given the supported extensions already here.
PAUL: Okay, so based on that, the simple validation will be done. I'm not checking whether the file is corrupt, those type of checks that can be done, okay? But for now, I've just kept it simple.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Okay, now coming to, few things, very specifically, because, loot from upload.
PAUL: Okay, so now this particular function, which I have, this is much more responsible to work with the API. So, whenever you are sending any type of file, okay, through server, okay, how will you be sending that?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: when you were sending it from client to server, or from SAM, were different. File uploads, but actually, like, if you do the upload, what take place?
PAUL: Base64, yes. Like, Base64 is,
PAUL: People are telling API, within the API, how it goes, from client to server.
PAUL: No, not SFTP. Right now, there is no HHTP protocol.
PAUL: Somebody's telling payload, but exactly how the payload is sent? Through bytes.
PAUL: That's the main thing, and probably it can be some type of encoding. Base64 is one of them. Right now, directly, I'm taking the binary input output, so this is the type of…
PAUL: file that I will be expecting from my API to be coming. Then I have passed a simple file name str, it means that when I'll be saving, so directly I'll be calling this function, and I'll be passing the name of the file, based on which I want.
PAUL: Now, here, the idea is that we have created some type of temporary file. Now, this is not always a practice. As you can see here, this is within that, try block. Like, you can create a temporary file for processing, and later on, you can delete that file also.
PAUL: Okay, as simple as that. Now, every time you don't need to do it, but I feel that it's a good practice. So, just because of that, I have kept it here.
PAUL: Okay, now, working with temp files, so if you remember, that's why
PAUL: Initially, this input temp file that I have used. The idea was to build something in the temporary phase, later on I can save it and write.
PAUL: It's a practice. The idea is that directly saving the file, it's better to take something in the temporary phase and then create.
PAUL: Right now, queues later on, those are pretty much advanced things. Right now, if you ask me why RabbitMQ and other things, I will bring into the picture.
PAUL: Alright. Now, the first part is, the part with respect to, getting the information from your API. So, very specifically for that, I have this particular function, which we'll get at, so let me take this one.
PAUL: And this entire approach.
PAUL: Like, again, like, I've seen many developers not using, temporary files. Directly, whatever comes, they can use Base64, or whatever the type of encoding.
PAUL: from the other end that they are getting, based on that directly, they can seek the file. So that process is also fine, just I wanted to show you that, yes, you can take this particular approach also.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: And at the end of the day, once you have saved your temp file, it is very important to undo an unlink operation. So that's why this unlink operation I am doing. Okay, because this is step. The idea is to do entire cleanup also.
PAUL: Now, once the file is available, in the next step, okay, so split the documents.
PAUL: Let's take this one. Now, this is where, if I call this class with this particular function, then your chumping will be applied.
PAUL: Okay, and as you can see here, what I'm calling self.textsplitter.splitDocuments. Where is split documents that I have defined?
PAUL: Okay, now this is the…
PAUL: actually, I can say, like, at any point of time, you can go through, but this is the actual text splitter class from Langchen through which we are looking into the text split.
PAUL: Okay, and this is our main implementation of our tech splitter, that we have already done it.
PAUL: Okay, now directly I'm calling that.
PAUL: Is this part clear with respect to split documents? At any point of time, if you feel that you don't know, please click on these things. Please click. Automatically, you will be redirected to the right place from where the call is coming.
PAUL: Moldent.
PAUL: Now, the split document part is done. Okay, so now this is the part where your chunking takes place.
PAUL: Okay, now, okay… Once the chunk is… chunks are available, Yes, sir.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, split. After the split is done, then in the next step, you need the documents.
PAUL: So, once you have this particular… okay, so this particular process file will return all of your split chunks.
PAUL: Okay, so load and split the file in one step. So, directly, can I call this, see, in this process file, what I am doing?
PAUL: I'm calling load5.
PAUL: Okay, so this load file option is there. And directly, I'm calling, this function that I've created, splitDocuments.
PAUL: Otherwise, directly also you can call, but I've just created a function within that. I'm keeping two things that separately I don't need to make a call. By making a single call, I can do the entire processing.
PAUL: Is this part clear? Why I have kept these two things in one place?
PAUL: Perfect.
PAUL: Now comes finally the, process upload.
PAUL: Okay, so now just process upload, so whenever, you are getting any type of document.
PAUL: Okay? So, like, through APIs. Like, whenever you look into process or upload, all these upload options, so these are majorly… it means that I'll be calling these functions during the fast API phase. Right now, initially, they are not important.
PAUL: Once I do the connection, what is the file type that I'll be receiving? It will be binary input, output, the file name, the string, so everything with respect to processing the upload. Now, in this process upload, what I have done?
PAUL: So, simply, first of all, I need the upload, like, whichever file that is coming from me, and then on top of that, I'll be doing the split document. So, see, process file and process upload. One is process file, like, within the system. Now, if you want to process the upload, in that case.
PAUL: Okay, so both the things that I've kept it, but again, process, uploads, sometimes it is not necessary, because right now, in Streamlead and other places, you really don't need. But with respect to FastAPI, I have kept it.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the main part with respect to your document processing. All the different type of processes, okay, that I'll be doing, or somehow they are connected to some intermediate services, all those things that I have mentioned here.
PAUL: Please let me know, like, step by step, that's why I've gone through each function.
PAUL: Through the document, processing responsible for taking the file correct, processing based on type, extension, and return the chunks correct. Because once the chunks are available, then what is the next phase?
PAUL: Once the chunks are done, what will be the next phase, the next file that we'll be working on?
PAUL: Okay, yes, so let's get into our embeddings part.
PAUL: Somebody's telling store to vector. Before storing, we need embedding, so… All right.
PAUL: frame.
PAUL: Alright, so… Let's discuss the file. So, similarly here, my main embedding is OpenAI embeddings that I have taken.
PAUL: Now, from app.config, getSettings and getLogger, getLogger. Now, these inputs will be pretty much in every file, because every file will have some type of settings, okay, which is related. For example, with respect to OpenAI embeddings, what is the setting that you are looking for?
PAUL: I can say embedding model.
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: Or probably, right now, I don't think I've mentioned dimension there. Probably somebody might take dimension also, the embedding dimension. Those are those type of settings, so at every point of time, these two things will come, okay, in your core services, the settings part and the logger part.
PAUL: Okay, now,
PAUL: using LRU cache, so this def get embeddings, and the output type will be OpenAI embeddings. Okay, now, this helps you only for local implementation, where you get catch-it OpenAI embeddings existence.
PAUL: And right now, to, do the embeddings, so simply, I'm calling the OpenAI embeddings function. So if you really look into Langchen underscore OpenAI, previous thing we have already worked with, and this is the actual embedding.
PAUL: That we are, using it. Now, this is very specifically for catching operation. That's why I've added this particular decorator of LRU underscore catching.
PAUL: What is the use of LRU catches? Really, like, people with Python… because if you're working, for example, with any type of explosive or pure functions, and you want to call it repeatedly with the same arguments, pretty much a recursive algorithm if I'm talking about. For example, API response catching.
PAUL: Okay, or computing-heavy transformations, okay, in, like, in our rack pipelines. In those cases, it is really helpful.
PAUL: Okay, because these are pure Pythonic stuff, nothing that is with respect to RAG that we are doing.
PAUL: Alright, now this is my main one, okay, which will get the ones.
PAUL: Yes, according to… you can think about a performance optimization by introducing Catcher, yes. Okay, now coming to my main embedding service. Now, this is the actual service, if you refer here.
PAUL: Okay, now, if you look into, this is your main embedding service. Document processor, we have gone through, now we are into the next phase. Once the embeddings are done, then I will go to the vector store part.
PAUL: So, in the embedding service, what are the things that I need, okay? So, first of all, initiating with get embeddings. So, now, if you really think about, this is actually… I… only two things are being written, the actual call to OpenAI embeddings using the Langshan package, and the settings for, the…
PAUL: call to that AI OpenAI third-party service.
PAUL: Okay? Now, if anybody wants to change your embedding, now this is the place.
PAUL: It means that if you're bringing your, Gemini embeddings, I hope everybody understands, this is the file that you need to change.
PAUL: Anybody who wants to use Gemini, be smart, and please change this input.
PAUL: What are the things that you need to change? Here, this particular import will also change, because as you will be, simply comment this line, add the Google Generative AI, okay?
PAUL: Change this part.
PAUL: Okay, and similarly here, like, the OpenAI API key, the parameter can be the same, but you can pass your Gemini API key. Now, this is the actual place where you are making the call, so you need to change this part if you want to work with Gemini. Similarly, if you want to work with Ollama.
PAUL: Okay, ULAMA, I won't suggest, because, again, we will be doing deployments. If somebody's using ULAMA during the deployments, it can be a problem. You don't… you won't be having a local access, that's why.
PAUL: Then another setup for, Ola Mine, Docker. Okay, that we are not going to do now.
PAUL: Alright, now this is the main call. Now, this call, I am attaching it within the service, so by passing these two parameters. Now, two types of embedding operations that I need. One is embedding the query. If somebody asks the question.
PAUL: That query embedding part is there. Okay, now this is that particular function which is responsible to do it. Then you have embedding of the documents during data ingestion phase.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: two types of main embedding stuff. One is the data ingestion, other is the query. So for them, I have two separate functions. Okay, I know that, okay, during… if somebody asks the question, I'll be making this call. And similarly, they embed documents during the data ingestion phase.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Now, this part… I will just take it, the embedding service.
PAUL: Alright, now, embedding service is done. So, after the embedding, what we need to do?
PAUL: Yes, after the embeddings, what is the next step?
PAUL: vectorize… Okay, well, getting the vector store. Let's get into the vector store now.
PAUL: Yogesh is asking why the embedding documents, returns the list of lists, because the return type of that particular function will be based on that.
PAUL: Okay, now, yes.
PAUL: So, generally, the output… what is the output of any type of embedding?
PAUL: Please let me know what is the output of an embedding.
PAUL: I hope everybody knows. If I say the dimension, there will be numbers based on the total number of dimension, and all of those will be float values. So it will be a list within that.
PAUL: Please do check always.
PAUL: All right. Now, coming to the part with respect to the vector store implementation.
PAUL: Alright, now let's get it here. So here, I do have an embedding dimension, so this is by default, 1536 daily, okay? So I will just get all my imports.
PAUL: And let me pick it here, and then we will start the discussion of vectors too.
PAUL: Okay? Now, when you look into what are the major imports that I have that I'll be working with, which is responsible to do your vector store, like, once the embedding is applied, you will be performing an upload operation. Okay, so first of all, langchainport.documents.
PAUL: So, why this document class I am importing?
PAUL: Because the chunks that you will have, it has to be in some format. Okay, so generally, if you want to do any type of changes from one format to one format, you can use this document class. So, at any point of time, every framework has a document class of their own.
PAUL: Okay, during the data passes also, you guys have seen.
PAUL: Now comes your… these are the main imports, I can see, which are responsible for your vector store operation. The quadrant vector store, which comes from the Langchen Quadrant package, then you need to make a connection to your quadrant client, so the main quadrant client package that I am using. Then a few exceptions, and a few models that I have.
PAUL: If you remember these things, we have discussed this part, because exceptions, every time I don't keep it, right now, during modular coding, I am keeping this, because there can be some type of errors during the call to the vector database. So, for that, that unexpected response that I'm taking.
PAUL: Okay, and now comes our distance and params. Now, already I have discussed this in the quadrant part. What is the purpose of using vector params?
PAUL: Distance, what distance that we'll be using?
PAUL: Please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: Amit Kumar is asking, use of dimension and vector store.
PAUL: Really, like, all those things Amita have taught.
PAUL: Previously. Okay, your cosine similarity can be Euclidean distance, Jacquardian distance, Manhattan distance, any type of distance metric that can come into the picture. Right now, we are focused much more towards the cosine part. Okay, and the vector params, let me know about vector params. Not MMR, but…
PAUL: Please load… let me know about vector params.
PAUL: Yes, guys, let me know in the chat.
PAUL: See, I have discussed this thing, so I'm asking.
PAUL: vector parents, what is the purpose? So, during, if you remember, I told you, if you're creating any collection.
PAUL: In quadrant. So, you have to use this vector params to define the dimension.
PAUL: Because, for your data, what will be the embedding dimension that you have taken? That will be the input to this vector parameter.
PAUL: Filters is fine. On top of collection, you can apply filters. Right now, filters are not important, but the dimension. For example, right now, we have created a collection with 1536. Later on, somebody came and he's telling that, no, I want to do an inject operation of 786 dimension. Do you think that it will allow
PAUL: It won't allow.
PAUL: Because during the creation, I'm telling my vector params will be 15-30 seconds. So later on, if somebody comes with some other dimension, simply it won't be injected. That is the idea.
PAUL: They need to create different collection, correct?
PAUL: Now, this is the part, okay, so again, a few things, get settings, okay. Now, can you see from app.core.embittings, I'm actually calling getEmbittings right now, okay, and getLogger.
PAUL: Okay, so this is a new thing, because settings and logger in every file, it will be there.
PAUL: Okay, now the embedding dimension that I have discussed, now let's get back to the part, okay?
PAUL: Okay, now let me add my catch here with respect to my main quadrant client call.
PAUL: Okay, now this main, now this is the part where actually I'll be making the connection from my local machine to the cloud cluster.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, see, at any point of time, when you see that I'm using LRU underscore catch, you will always look into that these type of main function calls will be a lot within the application.
PAUL: So, I want faster speeds. So, for example, here, if I kept it, I know that, yes, I'll be doing multiple times of content collection, yes or no, tell me.
PAUL: Yes or no. So that's why the idea is basically to use that particular catch-up part. Okay, similarly in embeddings, I know that I need this embedding service.
PAUL: Again and again, for query I need, for ingestion, so at every point of time, the function that you fill that, okay, which will be used a lot. In those cases, you can attach that decorator of LRU gacha.
PAUL: I don't know, like, many people don't use it, but for pure Python implementations, I feel that it's good.
PAUL: Alright, now this is the main actual call.
PAUL: or quadrant client.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Using the quadrant client, I have to pass my Quadrant URL, which is available in your .env file, and then the API key, which is also available in your .env file.
PAUL: Okay, now once the connection is done.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, okay, now our actual Vector's service. Okay, I will just take this entire Vector service for now.
PAUL: Again, now this is the part that we are going to discuss, so… What one does.
PAUL: Thank you.
PAUL: Okay, just Command-T here, okay.
PAUL: Now, the vector store service, just like our embedding service, service for managing all of your vector store operations.
PAUL: So, right now, within our, I can say constructor.
PAUL: the major, I can say the arguments that I have is… one is collection name. Okay, now you can pass the collection name directly to this class, or it will be picking up from the settings. So, if you remember, my collection name, rag underscore documents, that I have defined it here.
PAUL: Okay, you guys need a break, it's 10.35. Alright, let's go for our break, I didn't look into…
PAUL: The clock fine.
PAUL: Okay, now, any questions or anything, okay, you can ask me. I will do my breakfast also, but simply you can let me know in the chat. I will be looking into the chats.
PAUL: You wanna see, you can do it later on. See, I am not, doing this. Later on, once we have discussed the project, okay, I can take, a few people who want to get as contributors, and whatever the changes you want to do, do it.
PAUL: Okay, don't worry. First of all, see, the idea is that there are many students who are not comfortable with Python. Let them be comfortable, then we can add
PAUL: more and more level of stuff. I have no issue, but let's at least complete the basics.
PAUL: Mahante's check, somewhere it has to be called.
PAUL: Right now, if you don't see, later on during the API phase, the call can be there. Please check.
PAUL: Harvey, please go through your Python concepts, man.
PAUL: Because LRU catcher, nobody uses it, and they are a proper catching system in production, everybody uses, like Redis.
PAUL: Alright, Adam and I will let you go.
PAUL: Okay, timer I have to set. No, I forgot the timer for just a second.
PAUL: Good luck.
PAUL: 10 minutes or 15 minutes, please let me know in the chat.
PAUL: 15, everybody Italian. Fine.
PAUL: Ariane, it's totally up to you. There are a few things that I have done, it's not cheap. When I work on the project, I define my styles.
PAUL: It's totally developer to developer choice. There is no certain, like, 100% standard. The idea is to follow 80% of the standards, 20% comes from custom things.
PAUL: If you check my production variable names, you will be totally confused. Like, why the names of variable are based on movies.
PAUL: So, it's totally up to you, like, who is the main goal.
PAUL: Complete this course, Rishab, then move there.
PAUL: Generally, like, when you work with a CTO directly, okay, I work majorly with the CTO, so there are a few things that I can decide directly on my own.
PAUL: So similarly, like, once you start, then you can define your own standards, really. I feel that there are certain PIPED standards everybody should follow.
PAUL: Because if you're working with Python, Pepet is the most. And how many of you know about Pepit?
PAUL: Yes, are there people who don't know about PepeTier? Okay, you don't see the timer, just wait. I have activated the timer, probably not shared it.
PAUL: blocks, yes. I think you guys can see.
PAUL: Okay, people say, really, if you don't know these things, please go and learn Python.
PAUL: Because paper paid is, like, the first day, if somebody teaches you Python, they tell you about these things.
PAUL: He is new to Python, please be good, that's why…
PAUL: It's very important to be good in Python.
PAUL: That's why during hiring, I don't really check that if the guy knows about RAP. First, I have to always check that whether the guy knows about the programming language, the database, these things.
PAUL: These things are very, very important, because he or she might be very good in theoretical.
PAUL: And he can say everything, but later on, during practical implementation, majorly face the absence. So, it's good.
PAUL: So, please practice Python, people who are not comfortable.
PAUL: Alright, fine, expert. Like, if you're, at least good in one oriented, object-oriented programming language, like, if I'm talking about, she has also.
PAUL: You are fine, like, you can switch to Python. But study Python, spend at least one week or two weeks dedicatedly on Python.
PAUL: Because that's the entire project if I'm doing, I use Claude entirely.
PAUL: Okay, because I follow my own rules of set based on that. I do pass those things, and based on that, the code is generated. So I always maintain, like, few terms during the generation phase.
PAUL: Mudasar is asking, load from upload doesn't seem to be optimized. Later on, right now, I'm not focused on optimization. First, the application should work, then only optimization I can do.
PAUL: It's PEP8 somehow. P-E-P-8.
PAUL: Yes, first focus on building the simple app, then later on, optimizations.
PAUL: Okay, you guys can add whatever PRs, okay, later on, once this is… project is done, you guys can raise your PRs. I will merge it.
PAUL: Yes, yogesh, you can go through. That is a good course.
PAUL: How this rag is used in production? This rag won't be used in production, for sure. This is pretty much simple one, Lilith.
PAUL: The idea is that everyone should be comfortable with the things that we are doing.
PAUL: Because Project 2 and Project 3 is very important.
PAUL: But in general, we will come too. So, those type of architectures will come, because, see, right now, I'm not adding anything. Your Project 3, that is important. So there, I'll be talking about a lot of companies. This is pretty much nearby.
PAUL: Because now, in the other systems, what will happen, your main ecosystem of the deployment will be the same, only the core application part that will be upgrading with time.
PAUL: Right now, till now, I'm working Monmouth. It's not entirely completed.
PAUL: what I will share comfortably.
PAUL: Alright, mails I will check on Monday.
PAUL: Alright, fine. Guys, just wait, I'll be back, okay, in 5 minutes.
PAUL: 5 to 10 minutes, just wait, okay? Please don't write in the chat, I won't be looking up.
PAUL: Alright guys, so… I'm betting… Janos is asking, pipet means piloting and roof, correct.
PAUL: In my CI pipeline, I have added those.
PAUL: Okay, and if you want those type of, tests to be done with linting and drafts.
PAUL: That I have. How long did it create to write projects with your own complex creative styles and your new represent of how to build a strong?
PAUL: data structures… it comes with experience orient directly. I cannot say that even it took time for me.
PAUL: If you start working in Python for at least 1 or 2 years.
PAUL: I feel that you'll be in a good state to take those things.
PAUL: Okay… Nitesh is asking, will be having Streamlit slash UI-based implementation?
PAUL: Nitesh, to build an UI, you need something, an API. Nobody uses Streamlit in production.
PAUL: Streamlit is really, like, not up to them.
PAUL: Okay, just wait.
PAUL: All the mermaid diagram, I will share to you.
PAUL: Server utilization is fast-paced, widely used in production.
PAUL: I've used many servers, I've used…
PAUL: Tornado, I've used for Falcon, but right now.
PAUL: after 2021, I feel like, Past APK is quite clearly used.
PAUL: No, SKI, don't write code manually. Manually, it will take a lot of time.
PAUL: I use some type of tools.
PAUL: which API is better, sir? I have some basic idea on… Flask is good for beginners. Start with Flask, switch to FastAPI.
PAUL: Next slide.
PAUL: Start with fast, always.
PAUL: Use local LLM. Okay, Parandama, I have no issues.
PAUL: Whatever you want to use, you can do it. Later on, once we have discussed this, you guys can raise your PRs, okay, and based on that, I can do the match.
PAUL: Alright, so let's start our discussion.
PAUL: So, stop sharing.
PAUL: I think my Realme board speaker is fine, hold it.
PAUL: Sure, this is zip stock 3, I could just wait.
PAUL: the chats window… Hmm…
PAUL: Alright, now we will start working with the vector store. Now, in Vector Store, I do have multiple functions, and majorly, like, the functions are responsible to perform different type of VectorDB operations.
PAUL: Okay? So, right now, in this particular class, so the first function that we discussed was basically to make the connection to your quadrant cloud cluster, okay? So, this mainline Quadrant Client client will help you to initialize that particular connection.
PAUL: Then, in the next step, I have my vector store service. Now, here are all the major vector store operations that we'll be doing. Okay, so think about what are the major operations, if you are working in a vector store.
PAUL: So, the first can be something like creating a collection.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Okay, so in our case, I think I have kept mine. I have few functions that I have kept, not every function, but yes, now this particular function is responsible to check that whether the collection is available or not.
PAUL: Fine. This, I have kept it in the first step. Then comes adding the documents to a particular collection. Okay, now this is another docu…
PAUL: Another function that you have?
PAUL: Okay, so one is ensure function to check whether the collection exists or not. The second function, which is adding the documents. Okay, now, for every type of chunk, if you look into, I have generated a unique IDs for each document.
PAUL: Okay, and using those IDs, I am saving it. Now, right now, EU ID4. Similarly, you can switch, you can use some other algorithm also to generate the ID based on your custom implementation. There is no restriction in that. You can give IDs.
PAUL: It is not necessary to give IDs also, but I feel that it's a good practice to use some type of naming convention for these IDs.
PAUL: So, for every chunk, I am generating that particular ID.
PAUL: During that, document, or basically, like, add document phase.
PAUL: And when I'm talking with respect to adding the documents to the vectors too, so add documents means I'm pushing those embeddings to the vectors too.
PAUL: Then there is a search operation, like, on top of every
PAUL: like, collection within your vector database. You have to perform this operation, your depth search.
PAUL: And if you really look into, this is the only one line which is important, which is the similarity search activation that I am doing.
PAUL: Yes, this is a similarity search. Last time during our notebook implementation, also we have looked into. Okay, and right now, the top case settings, because during your retrieval, if you remember, this particular configuration is available,
PAUL: within your config.py. So here, I think somewhere I've defined this retrieval underscore key.
PAUL: So, this particular parameter.
PAUL: So, for that, this particular function is there, which is search.
PAUL: Now, this is a simple search. Okay, now coming search with scores. Now, this particular function is also available, within Quadrant, okay, where you can pass the similarity search directly with respect to scores also.
PAUL: Now, these demos, I've already shown you in that quadrant and Wuviate lectures, because if you really think about, this is only the major line which is doing the implementation, and this is the major line which is doing the implementation for both the type of searches. One is search with scores.
PAUL: Okay, and the other one is search. I think in my API, I'll be using search, not search with scores. Later on, if you want, you can create a specific route for this scoring mechanism.
PAUL: Okay, so two types of searches. One is without the scores, one is with the scores.
PAUL: Alright, then comes, getting your retriever. Now, this is the part where you initialize your retrieval.
PAUL: def get retriever. Okay, now as you can see, the return type is what? So, vector store as retriever, such type, similarity, and finally, the top key arguments that I am passing here.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the getRetiver function that I'll be calling it most of the times.
PAUL: Now, a few functions that I have, like delete collection, if you want to really delete a collection. If you want to get some type of collection info within Quadrant. Now, this is very, very specific to quadrant that I have written.
PAUL: If you change anything, if you change your vector DB, a lot of things that needs to be changed. I hope everybody understood this part.
PAUL: Because majorly, the code which is available here, it's only for quadrant. If you change your vector databases to some other, you need to change at every point of time.
PAUL: So right now, getting the collection info, so these are normal stats, okay, so written dictionary, name, points count, index vector count, status, whether it is available or not, otherwise simply through an info.
PAUL: What is the point count?
PAUL: Anybody knows about point count?
PAUL: Like, how many, documents are available, or, within that particular collection?
PAUL: Okay, that is referred to as point count, or, simply that they are, change the name.
PAUL: Previously, it was simple vector counting.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the collection info. Now, these are all related to VectorDB operations. Now, this can be huge. Generally, in production, this vector store operations, we'll be using more and more operations. Right now, I have kept few basic ones, the search, get collection info. Okay, then you can
PAUL: Add more and more things.
PAUL: Okay, because TB part, really, with respect to operation, this file really gets increased to more than 2,000 lines of code.
PAUL: Now, this is a part with respect to the health check, to check that if the connection is good or not. If you remember, here are also this health
PAUL: Is there. Okay, so we always check the, service, okay, that whether my vector store is connected with my application.
PAUL: Okay, for that, I am doing this. Okay, so true if healthy, false otherwise. Okay, and you have to always look into, like, get collections. Now, when you will be getting the collection, if the connection is successful.
PAUL: If you're passing wrong URL, wrong, key, do you think that this particular function will be, called, like, get activation? You will simply get an error. Okay, so that's why a simple health check for now that I have added.
PAUL: Right now, I'm not focused on metadata. Metadata later on, project 2, project 3, that I'll be focusing on.
PAUL: All right, then Quadra…
PAUL: No, you can use others also, Virajpatal, really. UVID is the most basic, simple implementation that we can do. Otherwise, you can define your own ID logic. Like, ESPDF, path name, in that way you can do it.
PAUL: There is no restriction. I have… see, this is the first project, I've kept everything simple. On top of this, whatever you want to edit, okay, later on, you can do it, after next week.
PAUL: Alright, this is the vector store service that we have defined. Now, once the vector store is done, what is the next call? Or what is the next operation?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: my own ratchet.
PAUL: So, for ranching, let's get back to our core service.
PAUL: Okay, my rack chain. So, generally, the rack chain, this part will be small only. Okay, now, here, what happens with respect to your,
PAUL: RAT chains, so everything that we have defined above. So, first of all, let's take the import part.
PAUL: Okay, now just look into the inputs. They're just, like, last time, okay, Langshan code documents, import document, you do have a string output parser, then you have a chat prompt template.
PAUL: Then, to make the chain runnable, so for that runnable pass through anything that you pass through the runnables, okay, it can be passed through a chain. And then, finally, my LLM, the chat OpenAI class that I am importing.
PAUL: Okay, and then finally comes that, okay, I am calling my vector store service here. Yes, it is needed, then getting the settings, and finally, the implementation of the logger, because settings and logger will be there in every file.
PAUL: Alright, now let's start with the First one, so…
PAUL: Document processor, I will close, embeddings, I will close, vector store, I will close.
PAUL: Good. Now let's get back.
PAUL: So, first of all, the RAT prompt template, okay, that we have defined here.
PAUL: So, I think, these two things you guys are already comfortable with.
PAUL: the rag prompt template and the format function, please let me know.
PAUL: These two things, everybody is comfortable with.
PAUL: rack prompt template.
PAUL: And the format of function, this, we have done it multiple times in every implementation.
PAUL: Okay, so… now these two things, I'll be directly passing it through the chain, but yes, these two…
PAUL: A lot of times you guys have looked into now coming to the main sport service, okay?
PAUL: Now, this is my main class, the rag chain class. Okay, I will just be just taking it.
PAUL: Here, other functionalities are there. Okay.
PAUL: But really, I am… Invote few things… But let's start the part.
PAUL: Till now, we have not discussed streaming. Okay, so…
PAUL: But I have kept a streaming-based response also, so that was available in line chain. Okay, so I've taken it. So right now, in the rack chain, what are the important things if you look into the constructor? Okay, so the first important parameter to this land chain is the vectors tool service, because
PAUL: In the chain, you need the top K documents, and from where you will be getting the top K documents, from the Vector Store service.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why doing a simple initialization, so vector store service, or moving to this. Okay, if it is available, so directly you can see it is getting redirected here.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, so, initially, so, my evaluator technique. So, do you think that every time I'll be using an evaluation? It's not important, so initially I have just initialized with none. Later on, I'll be,
PAUL: applying it, because I don't feel that at every point of time I need an evaluation. Okay, so later on, I can do the invoking. Here, I am setting the LLM configuration with Chat OpenAI.
PAUL: Okay? Now, I'll be getting my core information from here. This is the mean from where I'll be getting my top 4 chunks, okay, or top K chunks. Then, evaluation. So, initially, I'm keeping it as none. Later on, I will be updating this flag.
PAUL: Then comes initializing the LLM, so standard things, model selection, temperature settings, okay, and OpenAI. And if you really look into, all these settings are available within your, config.py.
PAUL: Okay, so if I go here, you can see automatically the config.py file will open.
PAUL: Now, we have the template, you need to pass it through the chat prompt template. Okay, so that, in the next step, we are passing it, so self.prompt is equal to chat prompt template, so directly the variable that we have used, we have passed it.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, after the chat prompt template, so now this is the part with respect to building your LCL chain.
PAUL: Now, in this chain, yes, we do have the retriever, self.retriever. Okay, so at every point of time, so self.retriever, you can see here the main retriever, which will be called from your vector store service.
PAUL: In the next step, you have your format docs. Again, this function that is already available in this file.
PAUL: Question, runnable pass-through, okay, at every point of time you have done it, okay, directly you cannot pass the question. To pass anything within the chain, you need to make it, pass, make it, like, be executed through that runnable pass-through.
PAUL: Then, self.prompt, so this is our prompt template that we'll be passing. Here, I'm defining, okay, this is the LLM selection that we have done, okay, from our self.lllm. And finally, our, this one, string output parser, which is coming, because the final output, I'm looking at in, the string format.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: Now, this part we have taken.
PAUL: Yes, line number 75, what? Runnable pass through any, it means that the quotient that I'm telling, because within that quotient, it's not only string that I am passing, so that's why I've taken any form now.
PAUL: Okay, now coming to… okay, now the logger is initialized, okay. Now, if you remember, initially, I have set my evaluated to none.
PAUL: Okay, if you remember, within my…
PAUL: constructor, self.Evarator, illegal to none. Later on, I can do the object, so this is the part where I am invoking the,
PAUL: RAG evaluator part
PAUL: Okay, now, getting or creating the rad evaluator instance. So, you can see if, self. is none from app code. Now, this is the implementation that we have not done yet. Later on, we'll be doing it. Because right now, leave the evaluation part, once we start working in the next file, where we'll be talking about the RAMs.
PAUL: Now, inside the rack chain, what was the first thing that we will receive? Can I say that query will come?
PAUL: Once the query comes, then only you will be invoking the chain, okay? So now this is the actual function.
PAUL: to do that. Now, in this, this is a simple query processing. It means that directly, the chain will be invoked, and you'll be getting the response. Okay, and this is your main variable, which is this answer, so that's why the return type of the function is directly written answer. But if you need something, like query with sources.
PAUL: Okay, if you need citations, it means that exactly from which file you have received that particular answer, okay? So, in that case, it is important, so that's why it's query with sources. Execute and write query, and return even the actual sources in your VDB, the vector database.
PAUL: So, from which it got. So that's why this particular function, again, so both are pretty much the same thing. Here, also, I'll be invoking the chain. Okay, but the idea is to get the source documents also. It means that with the chunk, we get that information. So, retriever.invoke. Now, in this case, I'm invoking that.
PAUL: Okay, now, formatting the sources, now this is a simple way to do the format, because when I'll be showing you, in the UI, at that particular point of time, you will be getting, okay, now this is the file name for this particular file, so these, for this particular query, based on the answer that you will be getting, so these are the specific citations that you have.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the part only with getting the citation. Now, you can see the return type is two things. In the last function, the return type was only answers. This time, I am telling that, okay, I need… I am… the return type is answer, okay, which is the output of the LLM, and then as well as the sources. And from where I'm getting the sources, from our retrieval.
PAUL: Yeah. No, I see.
PAUL: there are two functions. Now, I think everybody knows about asynchronous. Okay, so in production, this…
PAUL: It's much more preferred.
PAUL: Okay, because this query, I know that multiple people can come and hit this one. So that's why a simple async definition is the same function if you look into.
PAUL: Okay, so I've just kept both the implementation, the synchronous as well as the asynchronous, it totally depends upon you, which function you can call. If you really look into it, it's exactly the same piece of code. What I have changed here, only I have added one new term, which is async.
PAUL: Okay, and AWIT will also come at a later point, when I'll be invoking the chain. Only two changes, and the rest of the code is same. If you're not familiar with async, okay, an AWIT, please,
PAUL: go through at least the Python basic laws.
PAUL: Our wait is mandatory for async, yes, if you are working with async.
PAUL: After passing some with respect to the main function call, you have to pass await, because this is the actual chain which is getting input.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, another asynchronous function, getting the query waste sources.
PAUL: Perfect. Now comes, query with evaluation. So right now, I've not done any evaluation part, okay? But, for the query, can you look into that during the evaluation, I'm taking what are the answer as well as the sources? Because during your evaluation, you need this
PAUL: Because there are multiple metrics, generation metrics, retrieval metrics, yes?
PAUL: So for that particular implementation, I'm taking both the things.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: And, till now, I have not done any implementation for evaluation. Yeah, so from here, I'm… we'll be getting the main, content, okay? So right now, as this is the main key, for doing the evaluation, you can create a set also.
PAUL: And it totally depends, like, what type of metrics you want. So, for example, if you want only, metrics, which are not based on retrieval, okay, only focus on those two, like faithfulness and answer relevancy. That is also fine.
PAUL: Yeah, so it depends upon your use case. All the metrics, nobody uses. You can pick up only, I need these two, or these two.
PAUL: Alright.
PAUL: Now, this is the part where I will be initializing our evaluator. So, right now, see, the evaluation part, we are not done, so let's keep it for now.
PAUL: Okay, now this function I'll be talking a little bit once we have done the implementation of the Ragas evaluator file. Okay, so then this function will be much more important.
PAUL: Then, there is a string function that I have kept it. Now, the response type, okay, it means that when you
PAUL: make a query, okay? You do have the option of getting information in stream also. So, very specifically, we have not discussed this in class, but in Langchen, this feature is there. And I feel that when you have a very long output.
PAUL: Rather than, showing the user that, okay, you have to wait 10 seconds to see the entire output, it's better to show you the stream. So, step by step, all your characters will come.
PAUL: Okay, so streaming is good when you feel that the output might take a long time.
PAUL: To get your full output, I can see. That's why this particular function, I have kept it.
PAUL: streaming responses. So, one is the default response, and the other one is streaming response.
PAUL: All right, now this part is done. Okay, now this particular function of eQuery, evaluation, okay, so let's do the implementation of the RAGAS part, and then we will come back there.
PAUL: Yes, you can do. Wherever you feel the response time is higher, okay, it might take a longer time. Streaming response is one of the best options.
PAUL: pushed forward.
PAUL: Okay, now this is done, finally coming to our RAGAS evaluator, okay? So, let's quickly take the inputs.
PAUL: All right, so here, with respect to the metrics, okay, in our implementation, I think answer relevancy and faithfulness, two things that I have taken.
PAUL: Now, why I'm taking? Because if you are going to use
PAUL: metrics, okay, from retrieval-based, okay? Then you need to create a complete eval data set, and right now, I don't have the ideas to pass any type of document. So during runtime, I'm using only two metrics for now.
PAUL: All right, sounds, I think rest of the imports should be fine. Okay, this is from Hugging Face. Now, this is the actual invocation. Yes, no context recall. Context recall, context precision, those are retrieval-level methods.
PAUL: For that, I need an evaluation set. I don't have an evaluation set, if you pass any document. So, when your use case becomes fixed, then only you can do that evaluation part.
PAUL: In the meantime, I'm just using the core one. Later on, I know that you guys can do the implementation based on that.
PAUL: Alright, again, two synchronous and asynchronous functions that I have here, with very similar implementations.
PAUL: Later on, Pratamisha will be talking about that.
PAUL: So, let's start. Okay, now this is a main function through AGA's evaluator, for evaluating your RAG responses, and based on the input, I can see, okay, two generator-level metrics that I am using.
PAUL: Now, my main, constructor within that, okay, so get settings that I am passing. Now, see, all this information.
PAUL: Okay, I have already set it where?
PAUL: In my config, if you really look into everything which is there.
PAUL: Okay, so my chat OpenAI, my OpenAI embeddings… okay. And finally, the two metrics that I am using. So, the idea is to pass it as in a list. Later on, I can apply a forlook directly on self.metrics.
PAUL: Okay, so all these things I've already defined in my config.py, so from there, I'm actually picking it up.
PAUL: Raul is asking context precision, you know, you need expected output, but for context relevance, you don't need… for answer relevance, I don't need, yes, correct. For precision, I…
PAUL: Precision and recall, yes, you were correct if I needed.
PAUL: 100.
PAUL: Okay, so the logger part is done. Okay, now two functions, I think. Again, evaluate and evaluate whenever you look into the term A. Just be sure that, okay, some type of asynchronous, I think, that I have done. Alright, here are the asynchronous implementation that I have done.
PAUL: Okay, now, see, generally what happens, okay, there are multiple ways, okay, of, doing this implementation. Like, how do you want to do the evaluation?
PAUL: First of all, it means that
PAUL: Do you want to only show the answer to the user, or do you want the evaluation metrics also to be shown?
PAUL: Because if you don't fail, then you can run the evaluation in a separate threadful.
PAUL: Otherwise, the user might, like, need to wait for a long time. The evaluation process takes more time than generating the response.
PAUL: Always remember that.
PAUL: Because a separate LLM call will take place. So, that process, do you want to include it in your systems? Always take that decision from your side. That, okay, my users don't want the metrics, remove it.
PAUL: You, okay, behind the scenes, you can call a separate thread, execute that inside that, and keep it stored in some place.
PAUL: Probably in Landsmith, in other places, so many places. So, always remember that how you want to do the evaluation, you need to really plan that.
PAUL: Because I don't feel for end users, evaluation is so much important.
PAUL: Rather than for the mean… Back-end guys is more important, so try to keep it in a separate pool.
PAUL: Alright, now…
PAUL: Okay, now, calculating the total evaluation time, this thing I think I will return even in the API call. Okay, and then coming to the scores, okay, so these are the score definitions with respect to faithfulness, answer relevancy, and here I am passing. Okay.
PAUL: And I know that Jesus will be in the float, because what will be the max and the minimum value of faithfulness? It's between 0 to 1 always.
PAUL: Probably.
PAUL: Now, again, these settings, okay, evaluation completed, so these are all the logger implementation.
PAUL: Okay, if the evaluation failed, okay, again, it will simply raise an exception.
PAUL: Now, coming to preparing the dataset. Convert the RAG output to a RAGAS data format. So, for that, I have used a dataset package, if you remember.
PAUL: Because at least these three things to prepare a dataset, see, I have taken. Now, if you want generator metrics, generally, like, right now, we are focused on generator metric, but for retriever metrics, what is the other thing that you need? Because, see, if you remember the term relevance.
PAUL: Relevance, not relevance, referential. The actual ground truth.
PAUL: Right now, I don't have ground truth.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, it's a good practice to always keep your ground booth.
PAUL: without the ground truth, there can be, simply, like, a lot of problems. Right now, I don't have ground truth. What I can do, because I have to create that set.
PAUL: Now, three things that I'm taking for evaluation, okay, and the idea is basically to use the dataset. Okay, now this is basically the dictionary, and from there, I'm creating one sample here.
PAUL: return dataset dot from detect data, so this particular dictionary that I am passing, and it will help me to create that particular sample for the evaluation.
PAUL: Okay, now evaluate with timeout. Now, see, this is a very similar implementation, I don't feel every time you need it, okay, but sometimes the evaluation might take a lot of time.
PAUL: How many of you know about that? Because in some cases, it will be faster, in some cases, you do have a timeout issue. Because of that, I only have kept this particular function.
PAUL: Okay, I have seen that, generally, during the evaluation, what happens? Okay, like, if you want more level of evaluation, it means that with respect to generations.
PAUL: and the evaluation checks. So, generally, I've seen that when people do that, okay, the output from the LLM should be 3 different types, where you say that, okay, I need 3 different generations from the LLM.
PAUL: Okay, now similarly, from the evaluation LLM also, if you are doing three levels of generations, okay, three level of generations.
PAUL: Then, like, really takes a lot of time.
PAUL: 3 there, 3 here. In those cases that you need to compare those, so really it takes a lot of time, so very specifically, I've taken this time out with evaluation. Sometimes I feel it's important, because the actual function is this one, rather, evaluate.
PAUL: Okay, this is the actual function called. Rest of the things are pretty much Python boilerplate, but this is the actual function which I'll be calling for Ragas to start our evaluation, and everything will be saved within this result.
PAUL: Okay, and you can see this result I'm converting into pandas to date, and finally getting the record.
PAUL: Okay, now this is how I'm accessing it.
PAUL: Now, a separate function to handle any type of evaluation errors if I give these type of nuns.
PAUL: Okay, and it can happen, because right now, I'm just logging the results, and right now, as you can see, based on the exception, simply it will be helping to do the logging if I get any type of errors during our evaluation process.
PAUL: generally, like, you can drop it in F3,
PAUL: Or probably in some database with some webhook.
PAUL: Totally up to you, like, how you design that. There is no fixed rule in designing that part.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the RAD evaluator part, okay? If you really think about what is the core logic, okay? The core logic was only one thing. One was preparing the dataset. I feel this function is much more important. Once the data set is available, you need to pass it for your evaluation.
PAUL: Actually, only two lines of code, which is important.
PAUL: Other than that, rest are pretty much Python violet plates in most places.
PAUL: Alright, now, finally, when I'm calling my evaluate, okay, so here I'm using the asynchronous part.
PAUL: In the normal evaluation part, it's, this one is without the asynchronous, here, direct evaluation that can take place. Now, here, you can see, if you look into the comments, in production, consider using single.along or threading.timer. The idea is that to… you should do the evaluation in a separate thread, not in the same one.
PAUL: Alright, now the Ragas evaluator part is done.
PAUL: Okay, so I feel that my core main module that I had It is available.
PAUL: Okay, so, yes, this part is done, okay.
PAUL: Now, let's get back to rack chain. I think in the rack chain, there was a part with respect to evaluation, this, query with evaluation. Execute async rank query with the RAGAS evaluation. Now, see, this information that I'll be getting.
PAUL: From when?
PAUL: From the output of their ad?
PAUL: sources I'll be getting from the retriever, okay? So, if you look into… the Aquery with sources.
PAUL: Okay, finally getting the context from every sources, then finally handling our AE evaluates. So, by default, this function is getting caught. So right now, I'm using the asynchronous function, I'm not using
PAUL: the normal synchronous ones. Always do refer that actually in my chain, which function I am calling. You are totally free to change these functions, spend some time.
PAUL: Okay, I've used more asynchronous implementation, so that you guys get used to.
PAUL: And in production, everybody uses asynchronous-based task meeting.
PAUL: Okay, so from here, the main core evaluation will start, and you can see this is taking 3 parameters, the question, the answer, and context, and based on that, it will throw me the final result, which will be saved inside this evaluation period.
PAUL: Alright, now… The core application logic, the core business logic, we have done it.
PAUL: Now, whatever the thing that I'll be doing, it is Pythonic. Now, this is nothing related to your rack.
PAUL: Okay, because now I will start working on the API part.
PAUL: Because we need our API routes, if you looked into these core services that we have already covered, the ULOB part. Now, we will start working in this part, the blue part.
PAUL: The idea is to create the routes and make everything, to get connected with our core services. Okay? So let's start with the boilerplate. I think I will be having somewhere…
PAUL: A template of a file.
PAUL: racial… Somewhere, I think.
PAUL: With respect to my routes.
PAUL: Anybody have that app?
PAUL: Right, fine. So, from Fast API…
PAUL: Let me just take a simple… function.
PAUL: Now, see, I will be going back to my main root folder. Okay, so let's get back here, requirement.txt, okay? And let me just show you a simple boilerplate of FastAPI. Okay, so for example, main.py. You guys don't create main.py, okay? I'm just creating it for now. Later on, I will delete it.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the, like, whenever you start learning Fast API, okay, you will be getting these, very similar boilerplate, something to this. Okay, so generally in Flask, also, you do the same thing. First, the Flask class initialization, here for FastAPI that I am doing. These are two simple routes.
PAUL: Okay? So, two simple routes that I have.
PAUL: And in this route, so basically, I'm telling that it will be running in my local host, and by default, the port is at 1004 fast API. So if you try to run this, so what will happen?
PAUL: Let me just switch to… the terminal.
PAUL: Okay? And if I try to write here Python, main.py.
PAUL: I don't have any fast module, alright? Let me do… form, tomorrow's GPA.
PAUL: With respect to imports, I feel that, am I missing?
PAUL: Foster pairs? Dead.
PAUL: Just wait.
PAUL: Yes, this is working fine with respect to main.
PAUL: I don't think there should be… okay, alright, alright.
PAUL: My mistake.
PAUL: So, right now, this is… okay, now this is the command, actually, when you start the server. Okay, so FastAPI uses UVCon. I was directly executing it Pythonic way, okay, which is a bad practice for FastAPI. Now, UVCon, main. Now, main is the name of the file, see? Main is a…
PAUL: name of the file disk. Within this file, I have this app.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why the naming convention goes, like, name, then app, and then reload. Let me see whether it works or not.
PAUL: Okay, and right now, as you can see here, it is working fine. So simply, if I click on this one, okay, you will see that, okay, I'm getting this information.
PAUL: Welcome to FastAPI. Now, this is the first route that I have. So, if you look into the script.
PAUL: Now, this is the return type of slash. Slash means root.
PAUL: Okay, so similarly, I do have an Health, which is available here. If I go to this particular route.
PAUL: Okay, so for beginners, I'm just telling.
PAUL: If you're not familiar with this.
PAUL: Okay, status is equal to healthy, so right now it has changed.
PAUL: So, previously, it was FastAPI, now, in this way, we'll be creating multiple routes.
PAUL: As you can see here, based on this one, I need a route for help, I need a route for documents, I need a route for query. So, 3 different routes that I need.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Now, this implementation, I hope, like, I will delete it, but this is the core, part with respect to FastAPI, because I'll be creating routes, and right now, I think everybody knows about GET, POST,
PAUL: Okay, other protocols doesn't matter to me, at least with respect to APIs. GET and POST.
PAUL: Everybody is familiar?
PAUL: Alright, fine. If you're familiar, no problem.
PAUL: But right now, I will delete this file, because I don't need this one.
PAUL: Delete.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Now, coming to,
PAUL: API and routes, okay? So, initially, I'm, right now within my routes, and let's get back to GitHub, I think.
PAUL: This is a part with respect to sound… I guess so…
PAUL: within my app, I have my API. Within the API, two things are there. Okay, so first of all, let's…
PAUL: create our, init is pretty much blank. We do have the main schemas. Okay, so these schemas are based on
PAUL: pedantic models. Okay, so let's… Take, first of all, init… Just wait.
PAUL: within the API?
PAUL: Happy PI, okay?
PAUL: API plus underscore, underscore, init, underscore underscore dot PY.
PAUL: The other file is… schemas.py.
PAUL: Alright, so within the routes I have…
PAUL: APA?
PAUL: Alright, routes is blank. Okay, now, so let's focus on this, exactly what is there in the schemas, okay? Now, here, you will be having models, Pyntic models. As simple as that, it means that for every
PAUL: route, what will be the input, and what will be the output. So for that, I've defined these five intake modules.
PAUL: Now, first of all, the health response model. As you know that, there is some type of health check operation, so for that route, I've created this particular… the class health response, where I'm inheriting the properties from the base model. Okay, and what health will return? The status, okay, in the status, it will be string.
PAUL: status, what will be? Like, something in, I can say, healthy, not healthy, down, something like that. I know it will be a string. Then comes a timestamp.
PAUL: Okay, the current system time, you can see, based on UTC, the current timestamp that will be, thrown to you.
PAUL: Now, this is just to check, okay, just to do the verification that, yes, everything is working fine.
PAUL: Then comes your readiness check. Okay, now this is another check that I kept it. Okay, now, readiness check means that your connection to quadrant. So, quadrant connection, that's why that Boolean value is there, true or false. If you pass any wrong API keys, wrong URLs, you'll be getting that. And then, collection info date.
PAUL: So, whenever you will be doing this readiness check, you will be calling the function getCollection, if you remember in the code we have mentioned. That get collection will tell you that, okay, if the connection is successful, then we can actually get the collection info from there.
PAUL: Now, the next model that we do have in Pythake, okay, which is the…
PAUL: Let me close this one, yes. The document…
PAUL: upload response. So, whenever you will be uploading a document.
PAUL: Okay? From the client to the server. It means that to the FastAP server when you'll be uploading it. So there will be a message, the status message that, yes, there is successfully uploaded. The name of the file will come into the vector, the chunks that will create it, it will come, and the document titles. Everything will be written to you in one chunk.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why this is how the structure that we have defined. Like, after the upload, you will be getting all these messages in the response from the API.
PAUL: Then comes document info. If you want information about a very specific document, for that, you can pass the source, the metadata based on that. It will throw you the results based on document. I don't think I'm using document info right now, but I have kept it. At a later point, we can use it.
PAUL: Then comes document list response, response of the listing documents, so the collection name, okay, the total document, the status. Like, within a collection, you might have multiple documents. Multiple document means multiple chunks that I'm referring.
PAUL: Okay, so that particular final status, like, true or false, based on that, it will simply throw you the flag. Now, these are all data validation, really, like, data validation is not required, but it's a good practice. Going forward at every point of time, we will be doing this. Now, all these things that I have discussed, it's based on response.
PAUL: Okay, based on response only, now coming to the query schemas.
PAUL: Now, request for a rack query. The question has to be a string. Okay, the… then comes, with respect to description, this I'll be showing you. The minimum length, 1 half past the maximum length, 1000
PAUL: Now, you should always know what should be the size of the kosher.
PAUL: There has to be some limit. I cannot say that I can pass a question of 20 lakh characters.
PAUL: Yes, please let me know. Is it possible to pass everything?
PAUL: 20 lakh characters, 30 lakh characters. So, pass something. Generally, for rack systems, I prefer that. At least, there should be 3 to 4 words.
PAUL: Because in one word also, understanding the context is very hard. So generally, most of the systems there, you can prefer that at least 3 words should be there, or at least somebody's typing close more than 7 to 8 characters.
PAUL: Because if you write something bad, okay, nothing the rack can do, it will fail. So it's a good practice, always keep that particular system.
PAUL: It won't support only MS.
PAUL: Okay, right now, very specifically, the max length of the query, I'm telling it's 1000.
PAUL: Now, do you want the include sources? Now, this is a Boolean that I'll be passing it. Okay, now, these all… query params means these all things will be there when I'll be making the API call.
PAUL: Okay, so during the API call, when I'll be, making the query request, during that point of time, question will come, include sources, true or false, enable evaluation, again, like, true or false.
PAUL: Okay, now these are all operations you can… so it's… during the query, it's all about the question. But if you feel that I need the citations, enable this. If you feel that I need the evaluations, enable this. To make these parameters as true, true, true. And then, finally, your question that you have.
PAUL: Okay, Rahul, that's fine. Later on, like, query, decomposition, transformation, nothing I'm talking about.
PAUL: I'm taking a simple query for now, whatever that is getting passed.
PAUL: Alright, now, coming to the source document.
PAUL: Okay, now, within that source document, the actual content and the metadata, okay, to receive this, main document information, then some evaluation scores that I have kept it. Okay, now, for every evaluation score, I know, like, greater than, lesser than. Okay, so based on that.
PAUL: simple, like, the float values has to be between 0 to 1, so very specifically, I'm defining these things. Evaluation time, it can be anything, really, I cannot add a taken, but the time taken will be with respect to the evaluation in milliseconds.
PAUL: If something is failing, the error message will come.
PAUL: Then comes your query response model. Now, this model is important because, in the response, the things that you will be getting. First, the question that you have actually asked, you will get the answer, you will get the sources, the processing time, the evaluation time, everything. Like, the final answer that you will be getting.
PAUL: And some error schemas, I have kept it. The error response models, so… one is simple, like error message details, and these are common, not necessary to use. You can use your main exception classes also, but I have kept it here.
PAUL: So, your query schema, error schema, okay, and your response schema. Three different types of schema that I have passed for data validation.
PAUL: There is no wire. It's simply, like, I have done the implementation. If you want, you can add it later. I have no issues in there.
PAUL: See, guys, my job is not to include everything. My job is first to build something simple, so that everybody can adapt. It's not about adding every functionality.
PAUL: Alright, now this part is done. Okay, now I will jump to the next part, okay, where we'll be talking with respect to the,
PAUL: actual route.
PAUL: So let's go into the routes part.
PAUL: I have my API, you have the routes.
PAUL: Okay? Now, can you see here, based on routes, 3 different routes that I have, the document route, the health route, and the query route.
PAUL: Okay, so 3 different files for each type of route definition.
PAUL: First of all, let's start with the documents one.
PAUL: Ariane is asking, if we enable evaluation, what will automatically… say, by default, I have kept it false. If you want at every call during the API call, you have to make that parameter as trueI.
PAUL: At every call, if you want, to do the evaluation.
PAUL: Alright, now coming to, document…
PAUL: management, so this is the poor part with respect to the route. Who will do the document processing?
PAUL: Now, all the things that we have created. So, from Fast API, import API router, file, exception file, okay, then comes upload file, because here, we'll be performing an upload operation, HTT exception will be there, we'll be working with files, and majorly our API router.com.
PAUL: Now, from API.app.api.schemas, last file I discussed is basically the parenting validation model. The query model, the response model, and the error model. So, all those models that right now I am importing.
PAUL: So you can see every model I have not imported, only few that I have imported.
PAUL: Now, from app.core, document processor, so simply, I, first of all, I need the document processor service.
PAUL: then I need the vector stored service.
PAUL: And then finally, I'm initializing the logger.
PAUL: Okay? Now, the first one. Now, this route, API router. Anybody else use this API router? Because I know that
PAUL: Majorly, like.
PAUL: Some people might have not used it, and in a single file, you might have kept all the routes.
PAUL: Okay, that is also fine with me, but remember, if the number of routes increases with time.
PAUL: Probably you might have 30-40 lumps.
PAUL: Okay, then your mean file will become very, very long.
PAUL: Okay, so that's why I'm using this API router, that going forward, if you have a lot of routes, and similarly, like, you can create many, many routes. Okay, most of the time, I create more than 20 to 30 routes only for vector DB operations.
PAUL: Okay, so the idea is that you do this using the API router. Otherwise, in a single file, you have to write everything. So, really, not a good practice. If you have lesser routes, stick to that. Okay, otherwise, use the API router based off of it.
PAUL: Now, first of all, to initialize my router, okay, so for my document route that I have, so here I am passing slash upload. Now, this is my main route that I'm defining.
PAUL: Okay, for my document server, for my document processing, my main route is slash upload. It means that localhost 8000 slash upload, I will open this, automatically, this route will be activated.
PAUL: In this particular route.
PAUL: So the response model, I have taken it from the document upload response, and the,
PAUL: Error responses, like 400 and 500, you can keep a long list of responses here, so based on that, whatever the error responses that you will be getting, it will be thrown.
PAUL: Okay, now this, really, list of error responses can be very, very long. And initially, two things, like, with respect to invalid file type and processing error that I have kept it. I know the error, so you should always know the list of errors.
PAUL: Summary, upload and ingest a document. Okay, and this is basically the description that I'm giving this particular route, which will be included in your Swagger UI. Till now, I think I have not shown the Swagger UI.
PAUL: Alright, fine. When I will start this server, then I'll be showing you the swagger.
PAUL: Then comes async dev upload document. Now, this is the part where I'll be uploading the document. Okay, and what will be the output type of this particular function? The document upload response.
PAUL: So, I've already defined the data validation technique for this particular route. Based on that, I'll be getting the response, then the logger is initialized. Now, validate file, if not file name, simply the exception will be raised, and status code 400, like, invalid file type.
PAUL: Because we have supported extensions, if you remember.
PAUL: Yes, guys, if you remember, we do have supported extensions, so that's why it is important. Then, in the trial log, I'm calling the entire document processor.
PAUL: If you remember, I created an object of our class, DocumentProcessor. Where is our Document Processor?
PAUL: Now, if you go to app, then Core, okay, let's close this, Core, my document processor. Okay, and from here, the main class.
PAUL: the document processor. This is the main one that you'll be calling. If you… so, I have created an object of this class, which is the processor. Now, using that object, I'm calling process upload. So, process upload is here, I think, somewhere.
PAUL: Process upload has to be there.
PAUL: Okay, this process upload function that I'm invoking.
PAUL: Now, generally, like, the idea is that we'll be getting the chunks, but there can be a condition that if there are no chunks which are rated. So, simply, again, an exception that will be raised.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, once… if the chunks are available, okay, then you can initialize your vector store service. So, vector store, if you can do, so simply created an object of the class vector store service, then I'm doing the add documents, right here.
PAUL: Okay, so add documents, so now I know that it will be pushed to your quadrant.
PAUL: Now, once your documents are pushed, do you think that there is any other task which is remaining in the data ingestion phase?
PAUL: Please let me know.
PAUL: once the documents are uploaded to VectorDB, do you think that it is
PAUL: there is any other task in the data ingestion phase. I can say that it's pretty much done.
PAUL: Okay. Now, that's why at the end, there are some few value errors with respect to exceptions that I have kept it.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Now, measly, if I say about this particular route, this route is more important. Okay, always remember this slash upload from line number 18.
PAUL: tell your line number 76. Then I have another router within the documents, which is basically the info one. If you want the document list, get the collection information for those type of tasks. So if you really look here, what are the things that I am doing? One is getting the collection info.
PAUL: Okay, like, getting the color… basically the statistics for the collection. Now, this is generally returned by the quadrant.
PAUL: And based on that, I have passed… okay, so in my responses, I can see the collection name that will be written, the total number of documents that will be written, and finally the status.
PAUL: Okay, and finally, our exception that comes. Then another function that I have kept within the document, which is the delete, if you want to delete a collection. So, for that also, I have given you the option right now. So, generally, you have to understand in production, this vector DB operations will be really, really long.
PAUL: Okay, really, so many routes will be there for every type of task.
PAUL: Okay, now this is the delete part, where I'll be actually calling this particular function delete collection. Okay, so delete collection is available, I think, within the vector store.pwifi. As you can directly see here, this is the actual call that I am making. Okay, so collection deleted successfully, and finally, it will be logged here. Okay, and it is done.
PAUL: Now, this is the part with the first route, with the documents.
PAUL: Now, I will move to the next part, which is the health. Health, there is nothing, really. Okay, if you really look into the initial router.get, so the basic health response check that I am doing, okay, I have passed it here.
PAUL: slash our ready route is there again. These routes are not so much important. If you have one health check, I feel that it is more than enough. But I have two different checks. One is the readiness check, and another is the health check.
PAUL: Now, with respect to the readiness check, it actually looks for whether, it is connected to the vector DB. That vector DB part comes into the picture. So that's why I'm initializing my vector, created an object of vector store service, and through that, I'm calling the health check. If you remember, this health check gets your
PAUL: the collection, info. Okay, I think somewhere here in this file.
PAUL: Alright, depot check.
PAUL: Actually, I have to open the file type. But to show you quickly, for your vector store, the last function was the LCH. Okay, get collection. So here, simply, I'm looking into the total. I know that if it returns a number of collections, the result is fine.
PAUL: Okay, so two simple checks with respect to health that I have, and then finally comes to my query.
PAUL: endpoints.
PAUL: So, input time, okay, so fast API responses, okay. Now, here, the idea is that if you want streaming responses, so very specifically, you need to import the streaming response, otherwise only response also comes. Okay, so right now, as I have the feature of that streaming response, so I've imported it right now.
PAUL: Now, these are all the schemas that I have defined. The error schema, evaluation score, query request, query response, source document, all the schemas that I am importing. Okay, so these are all for data validation purpose.
PAUL: Then I'm calling my rack chain.
PAUL: Okay, because this is the main class that I have.
PAUL: Okay, that I have defined, so this is the actual class rack chain that I'm initializing.
PAUL: Then I'm initializing my logger. Okay, now starting with our main API router. Okay, prefix slash query. This is the main route for your query application.
PAUL: With respect to your query, again, we already have defined the query response, error response, all these things that I'm importing. Okay, so right now, this will be a post call, so that's where router.post.
PAUL: Response model, the query response from that Pydentity class that I'm defining are very similar, like, invalid requests or query processing errors for those… these two responses that I'll be passing to error-based response.
PAUL: Then finally, initializing your query. To make your query, okay, what is the thing that you need to invoke?
PAUL: Only one class is here, the rack chain, okay? I need to make it pass through that, runnable pass-through, if you remember, whatever the question that we'll be getting.
PAUL: So, first of all, I've created an object of the right chain class.
PAUL: Okay, if request.inelEvaluation. Now, see, this is the condition that I'm looking at, if it is true or not.
PAUL: Okay, if… so, very specifically, if this particular condition is true.
PAUL: Okay, result of it, okay, a query with evaluation. If this condition will be true, then it will be executed.
PAUL: Okay, if it is not lisdirectrequest.com, this include sources welcome.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, if you look, so this entire loop will come when?
PAUL: If I have done some type of execution with respect to that evaluation part, really, I need it. Otherwise, by default, from the params, you can do it.
PAUL: And now, the idea is to access within your citations. So right now, request.question, the actual question that I'll be getting from the user, then including the sources, the request.include sources that I'll be getting from the retriever.
PAUL: Now, with respect to your source document, I know that I'll be getting the information with respect to content, and right now, though I don't have metadata, but I have kept one field here for the metadata.
PAUL: Now, for sources in the result, finally, let's look. Otherwise, return none.
PAUL: This is fine, okay. Else, and the answer is equal to this final result that I'll be getting after invoking the chain.
PAUL: Okay, so from here, the main result that I have, okay, which is result, within that, I will be having the key, that's it.
PAUL: Okay, and then finally, like, evaluation scores for that, every result that I'll be getting.
PAUL: Now, at every point of time, if request, now, if this condition is, false. Okay, so all this, like, do you want citations? So, I've kept all the citations based on that.
PAUL: Okay? Now, once this conditions are there, so two major conditions that I have kept, enable evaluation and include sources. Both the conditions, by default, it will be false. If you enable them, then only it will be enabled.
PAUL: Then comes the final processing time from start time to end time. Based on that, I'll be getting the result in milliseconds. Okay, logger.info, and this is the return type of the entire route.
PAUL: the query response model, where question is equal to request.question, answer is equal to answer, and finally the sources that you have. And based on that, the processing time that I am calculating. So, all those things will be written to you.
PAUL: It means actual question, the answer, the sources, the processing time, and the evaluation, if all the conditions are satisfied.
PAUL: Is this part clear? Because now we have done with respect to the query part. Now, I do have another query, which is basically the streaming query.
PAUL: Okay. Now, for that, you have to just change one main import, which is this one, radchain.stream. Now, this is how in LandChain you do, basically, generate a streaming response. Only this part will change, the rest of the code is pretty much the same.
PAUL: And during the, streaming response, you have to define what type of media. Right now, I know that majorly it will be text.
PAUL: So, the type of streaming response that needs to be defined, and I think then we have a final exception.
PAUL: Then there is a search.
PAUL: Because once you have the query with you, you need the search, because at the end of the day, you need to do an initialization of the vector search operation.
PAUL: Okay, so for that, again, you do have a function. So, async, dev, search documents.
PAUL: Okay. Now, generally, if you are performing a direct search on top of your vector DB, what will be your results?
PAUL: Can I say that those will be results of top K chunks, or based on whatever parameter that I'm doing?
PAUL: Yes or no?
PAUL: If I'm… if I'm doing any type of search operation.
PAUL: directly on top of VectorT, okay, without attaching the…
PAUL: LL. So, I can say that, yes, I'll be getting my raw documents, whatever I have fed it in the VDB.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, within this particular post, okay, so I do have a search document, and right now, if you really look into, I'll be initializing or getting the vector store service, so for that.
PAUL: So, generally, sometimes I keep the try block if I'm getting some errors during building the project, but it's a bad practice to keep your imports here. Later on, please switch every input to your top part.
PAUL: Now, vector store, okay, search with scores. Can you see this one? Now, this is important, like, every time within the
PAUL: I can say chain. I might have used only search, but if you want to initialize this search, then also that can come.
PAUL: And finally, what will be the input to this request.question? From where I'll be getting this request.question.
PAUL: Okay, the main quotient STR field, that I've defined it in the schemas. Okay, for taking the, user pig.
PAUL: And based on that, again, the same thing with respect to the return type of the documents. Now, for every document, one more parameter will be added, which is shown by, like, for every document, okay? Now, this is the relevance score. Similarly, like, content and metadata previously also used to get, but for this search.
PAUL: Okay, it means that similarity search with scores that you are actually doing.
PAUL: Okay, and this is the final return type.
PAUL: Okay, and finally, this query part is done.
PAUL: Okay, now tell me, because in our implementation, we have done it till schemas, I think, okay? I need to add my routes, so let's open the route folder.
PAUL: So, underscore, underscore, init, underscore underscore dot PY,
PAUL: Okay. Now, the next file we have is document.py.
PAUL: I think this was the name, let me have a check here.
PAUL: API. Inside the API, we have the routes in it, okay, tokuMeltz.py.
PAUL: Right?
PAUL: The other file that I have is health.py.
PAUL: Yeah.
PAUL: And the other file that I have is query.py.
PAUL: query.gvail.
PAUL: Okay, now I will just take the main code, so let's move to GitHub. Let's first take documents.
PAUL: Okay, I will copy the entire raw file.
PAUL: So, documents…
PAUL: Okay, so document is done. Now let me bring the content for health and query.
PAUL: Okay, sobrisos.
PAUL: health… Readiness check and health check, two checks are here, fine.
PAUL: Now, let me get here from… Sweetie.
PAUL: Alright, so majorly, I feel the configuration part
PAUL: is done, because this is our mean one.
PAUL: And with respect to this, I feel majorly some configurations that we have done it. I don't think any other major changes are there. But let me do a final verification. Okay, schemas I have not added. Fine.
PAUL: Let me add the schemas part.
PAUL: within the API?
PAUL: Schemas, alright.
PAUL: So, pyrentic schemas are done.
PAUL: So, init schemas.py.
PAUL: Okay, init with schemas.py, fine.
PAUL: Please do let me know if something, if I might miss, that's fine.
PAUL: Because the only one folder that I'm worried about Is this one, okay?
PAUL: Right.
PAUL: Alright, now coming to our final few files. These three files are remaining. Okay, the main actual, like, the entry point of the application. I think config, have I created config? Okay, so let me just close the routes.
PAUL: Hmm… Here, core also I don't need. Yes, I do have the config with me.
PAUL: Okay, other than that, yes…
PAUL: API also let me close. Config, alright, fine.
PAUL: Then let me get the mean.py, which is basically the entry point of the application.
PAUL: Yeah.
PAUL: Fine, I will discuss this part, don't worry. So, first of all, let me take the entry, and then I will do it.
PAUL: Brooklyn White.
PAUL: Underscore, underscore N8 underscore underscore dot Ey.
PAUL: Meanwhile, main.p, right? This is the one.
PAUL: Good.
PAUL: Right.
PAUL: It's not the major configuration with FastAPI that I'll be taking it here. Now, see, a few things that I have taken, because as I was working with the other branch, here you can see the UI branches there. Okay, so because of that, some static files you might see. But right now, it's not important, because the UI integration, I was working with it.
PAUL: But right now, I'm focused on the backend. Probably next week, we can talk with respect to the UI part.
PAUL: Okay, because in UI, simply, I will say this is the folder. I'm not going to teach you JavaScript and those things. Okay, you have to directly do the integration.
PAUL: Any use of embed query and embed document functions?
PAUL: I think, yes, somewhere, I think I might have used it.
PAUL: Because embed query and embed document will come into the picture. Without them, how can I initialize the embeddings?
PAUL: Right now,
PAUL: Majorly, the imports with respect to HTML response, JSON response, cost might evolve. So, this is a common boilerplate if you're working with FastAPI.
PAUL: Okay, right now, request for sure, to initialize our app, I need fast API, course middleware, inter-server connections, HTML response, JSON response, and static fill. This is much more towards the UI side.
PAUL: Now, the things that I'm importing from app import underscore underscore version. This is the initial app version that I discussed. I'll be passing that at every development stage, I can increase the versions.
PAUL: Then comes your app.apiroutes import documents health query.
PAUL: Okay, so at any point of time, if you don't feel, always look into, because somewhere I have defined exactly what is the version. Probably it can be somewhere within init, or probably. I think within app.
PAUL: this particular implementation, I have not taken. So, let me just take that.
PAUL: This is coming from… Okay, I think app underscore init.
PAUL: APP, this is the init file. Okay, now this is the version that has been defined here.
PAUL: Simply, like, copy-paste it.
PAUL: Okay, as you can see it.
PAUL: You can keep, otherwise, like, keeping something in the init, it's… you can keep it blank also.
PAUL: It's not necessary you pass everything always in the init.
PAUL: But sometimes you can keep your main responses.
PAUL: Perfect. So… When I look into my main.py file, so let's get back.
PAUL: So, right here, the things that I have imported, so my .env file, everything from there. Okay, now this, actually, I've kept it, because when I was working with Landsmith, I was getting an error. Okay, otherwise, I keep it always towards the lower side. So, just for a quick fix, I have added it.
PAUL: Context link with Leasing Context Manager, okay, for Fast API that I've taken.
PAUL: Now, in the next step, let's get all the settings. Generally, the idea is this, through this particular setting implementation, you can import your .env variables also. But sometimes, I feel that it creates a problem. Okay, because of that, manually, I've hard-coded these two lines here.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, this is the part with respect to the import. Like, from .env import, then I'm loading my .env files. I'm using async implementation in FastAPI, so for that async context manager that I am using.
PAUL: Then, my fast API with the request.
PAUL: Two important things, whenever you are working with APIs, you need these two imports in Fast API. To handle course error, you need the course middleware. How you want your response to be there, so HTML-based response or JSON-based response, both are supported by Fast API.
PAUL: And finally, coming to static files, okay, I think in my project, there will be a folder called a static, if you really look here.
PAUL: Okay, so this is a static folder, okay, where you have some CSS, JSS, okay, and index.html.
PAUL: Okay, so… now, based on this.
PAUL: I have taken those static files into account.
PAUL: Now, first of all, defining a lifespan for this particular FastAPI server. It's…
PAUL: important, I feel that… how many of you have used context managers?
PAUL: Okay, because this is just for implementing my FastAPI call.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: This, anybody has used it? Previously, context managers. What is the main purpose of using context managers?
PAUL: Everybody, like, in any programming language, context managers are always there.
PAUL: Generally, using Context Manager, you can handle what is the startup, the shutdown logic, as simple as that.
PAUL: Okay, so within the context manager, I'm telling you, okay, now, this is the light for this API call.
PAUL: Thank you.
PAUL: like a CloudWatch script, not exactly a CloudWatch?
PAUL: But, mainly, this defines what is the lifespan of your main function call. Based on that, I can actually change or update things. So, right now, the main thing I'm looking for is the startup of the application, the other one is basically the closing of the application. For that, I am defined.
PAUL: He has to handle smooth start and shutdown of the server pretty much correct.
PAUL: Now, this is my main initialization, see? Okay, and in the description, it's a pretty long piece of text that I have added. You can see a lot of information with respect to version, docs URL, redoks, open API URL, okay, few things that I've kept it.
PAUL: Because of OpenAPI.json, I don't feel I have it.
PAUL: But, let's see.
PAUL: Probability can be there somewhere.
PAUL: So, now this is the fast API initialization. Really, you don't nothing. If you want, just,
PAUL: Remove title, remove description. Just keep app is equal to Fast API, bracket open, bracket, closed up. Okay, now this is something, just to show you. Okay, when I show you, or basically when I try to open my fast application, within your slash
PAUL: The root part.
PAUL: Otherwise, this type of informations are really not required. You can just keep FastAPI blank, okay? So, simple bracket, open bracket, close. Now, I am allowing my course, and in course, you can see, allow origin physical to star. It means that from anywhere I get request, everything that I'm taking, star, star, star.
PAUL: Otherwise, in origins, what do you add? IP addresses.
PAUL: Yes, if you want a very specific server, okay, this should only be coming. You can add the IP of that, and from that specific server, you can take the request. Yes, whitelisting.
PAUL: All right, then coming to mounting static files. Now, see, this is only for the UI part, okay? Really, it has nothing with the backend part. If you're doing an UI-based integration, then specifically that particular folder which you have in your root.
PAUL: Okay, slash static, that I'm doing a mount operation.
PAUL: Now, I need to get my routes, all the routes that I have defined, within my app. Okay, so one by one, each router that I'm defining. So, first of all, app.app is the fast API initialization. Now, I'm including the routes. Include router, health router, then comes your document.router and query.router.
PAUL: Now, all the routes that you have defined within your app.
PAUL: So, this is your app, API, routes… okay, now all these three routes that I'm actually calling.
PAUL: Alright, now, once with respect to routes, we are done.
PAUL: So, first of all, let's start with the basic one. So, you can see here, app.getslash. Okay, now, here, I do have an index.html, but
PAUL: Initially, if I don't… okay, so I think the UI integration is done, that's why, because of this, the UI part is telling. Okay, so it means that I do have an index.html, so using simple HTML, CESS, and Bootstrap, a simple UI that I have created.
PAUL: Now, coming to some type of exceptional handling that I have kept it, and based on that, if some type of errors that I do get, so I'll be getting a JSON-based exception error. And finally, coming to the part with respect to starting my application. So, import uvicon and uvicon.run.
PAUL: I'm passing all the parameters. Your app, main, host, setting, port setting, reload is equal to true. In production, don't make reload is equal to true, make it false. Only for development purpose, reload is equal to true should be used.
PAUL: Now, this is the main core part with respect to exception that I have defined, and this is my main road path. Okay, fine.
PAUL: So, core things we have discussed. Now, this file that I should, instantiate once.
PAUL: So, let me take this one.
PAUL: Okay, so my main.py file.
PAUL: My main… where is my main? Okay, this is my main.piFi.
PAUL: Let me just close every photo.
PAUL: Okay, I have already kept it.
PAUL: Now, if I, try to add something here, okay?
PAUL: So, I think I don't have any more important things.
PAUL: Okay, one thing only I'm worried about, because that static mounting, All I have.
PAUL: Not taken into account, because in my… if you remember, Here, what I have done…
PAUL: this app mounting part, but I don't have the static files here for the UI.
PAUL: Let me just, add an hash here.
PAUL: Mmm…
PAUL: Okay, and my… main route, I'll be doing some updates. Okay, so…
PAUL: Okay, I need the list of commits, not a single commit.
PAUL: Alright, this is the merge request.
PAUL: Contributing, leveraging CICD.
PAUL: Great, just wait.
PAUL: I'm just going back to my old commit just to get the exact file that I had in that particular commit, okay?
PAUL: So I think this is my main.py.
PAUL: my main initialization with course, include router. Okay, now this is the actual function I was looking for.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: because I don't have an EUI right now, so simply, I can take that.
PAUL: get, okay, now this is the actual function, but I want to update it here.
PAUL: All right, because, see, without the UI right now, I'm doing the task. So, based on that… okay, so I just checked into, because I remember I initially started without an UI, later on, I added it. So, rest of the code looks good to me. So, I've done that.
PAUL: check my commit, the first commit that I have done in this codebase.
PAUL: Okay, whoever is asking, please go through the style that I go. Don't ask code from me. Ask me the process, how you got it.
PAUL: Okay, this is the first push that I have done. Code-based pushed, go there, and check the main.py file content. From there, pick up your app route that I have done.
PAUL: All right.
PAUL: Docker compose REST file, I think there is no such change, alright, fine.
PAUL: Now, I will start whether the app is working or not, because at the end of the day, if there are some errors, okay, I will try to look into.
PAUL: I think my main is within the app folder.
PAUL: Yes?
PAUL: Docker next week. Right now, Docker is not important.
PAUL: Alright, so now the idea is basically to see that whether the app is working or not, okay? So, for the execution, I will try to start the app. If I get any type of errors, okay, simply I will, let you know. So that's why I'm using this reload right here. Okay, I know that I will get some errors. Some errors has to be there.
PAUL: Without errors, like… cannot start working, okay? All right.
PAUL: Let me just open, okay? Fine…
PAUL: Alright, this is HTTP OK, alright.
PAUL: Then comes slash dots.
PAUL: Okay, alright, I think two times I have added slash.
PAUL: Alright, now, this is the part with respect to your swag anyway.
PAUL: So, simply, you can see, this is how the Swagger UI looks like. Okay.
PAUL: Commit, get it, the idea is, see, when you look into my commits, please, check the first commit. Within that, whatever is from main.py, copy the entire file. Rather than removing the function, if you are confused, take that entire file, just like I have done.
PAUL: And just be sure, take your time, 5 minutes, do the setup, if something is missing, I will wait 5 minutes, have no issue. How to open the Swagger UI? Localhost, 8000, okay, slash docs. Now, this is the one.
PAUL: local host.
PAUL: Then put 8000 slash drops, okay? Please take your time, I'm not in a hurry. Everybody, please try to say, I know many people will get the errors, something, because entirely copy-paste, when you try to do, I know there can be issues.
PAUL: But take your time.
PAUL: Swagger document is always gets auto-generated. That's the feature of Swagger.
PAUL: Please show us the command.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: please check, see. Don't always ask, show, show, show, guys, see? Always go to your GitHub.
PAUL: I think… where is your GitHub? This is not your GitHub. Where is DR? Yes. Ctrl-S.
PAUL: Go to your codebase, okay, check here, okay, learn about how steps are there. Get clone, okay, UVSync or pip install. Once you have done every setting, here you have the command to run it.
PAUL: please always check your README files before asking, because majorly the content I have shared it in. So please go through, take your time, 5 minutes, go through the entire stuff, and then please let me know.
PAUL: For anyone, the Swagger UI has launched, it's fine, okay? Others, please check. I know for a few people, it will work, and for a few people, it can be an issue.
PAUL: Amit Kumar and Quadrant URL, why will pass the port? Quadrant URL is the direct URL that we have used.
PAUL: Alright, Viraj, I'll be talking about that, don't worry. Right now, just focus on the core part of the application launching.
PAUL: Everybody, take your time, go through.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Others, please let me know for how many of you it is working, and for how many of you it is not working.
PAUL: Okay, Ariane, later on. Okay, one-to-one, I will do it for you. Don't worry, just wait, Ariane.
PAUL: Viraj, working for you, great.
PAUL: Rahul is asking, getting it, but right now, I've not done any integration with Landsmith. Next week, I will do Landsmith.
PAUL: Alright, people who are getting error, that's fine, I know few people will get it.
PAUL: Alright, majorly, for most of you, it's working, okay?
PAUL: Don't tell no module named FastAPI, just be sure you are
PAUL: Using the correct command, because in requirements, I have already shared FastAPI. So take your time, try to debug.
PAUL: Okay, working for me, working for me, okay, meaning I've been told, but fine. People for whom not working, please try to check.
PAUL: If somebody is getting OpenAI API key missing, please fill, provide your OpenAI API key, Naga.
PAUL: Alright, Amit, it's working fine. VectorDB running, shall I start the talk? Right now, nothing in Docker. Docker, next week, I will start.
PAUL: Today, everything I don't want to put in one shot.
PAUL: just say that at least, are you getting the CY?
PAUL: Pratamesh, already I have one content. Okay, drop me your mail, I will share it with you directly.
PAUL: Okay, Pratamesh, you drop me your name.
PAUL: I will drop you the other… few other things also that I have.
PAUL: Don't share your logs. In the logs, like, not… See anything wrong.
PAUL: Please show me the console. Console means terminal are you talking about?
PAUL: Mithage getting an internal server error.
PAUL: Alright, see, till now, I have not checked the routes. Even for me, also, it might not be working, but at least…
PAUL: Are you guys able to see the Swagger UI? Once you guys confirm, then only I will start testing the routes.
PAUL: Now, Rahul is asking, rather than Swagger specs, can we ask… make the system API through integration test?
PAUL: KSync can do that. Add all your call-based commands.
PAUL: Whatever the commands, you can create a test file Raul within that, based on that, you can add all your curl-based requests, just to check that, whether it's working.
PAUL: In that way, also, it is fine.
PAUL: Okay…
PAUL: Open slash docs after that PGPEG0774, after that, add slash docs.
PAUL: After 8,000, slash docs, please add it.
PAUL: Manisha Sharma, no module named… just check you have your init files. If init is not there, it can be a problem.
PAUL: Okay, Nobir's working for you, great. Peg working, Abhijit opened all right.
PAUL: I already have sent it, Pratamesh, app at the red question.in. Drop me there.
PAUL: Nagesh working, okay? So, majorly, for every one of you, it is working, few people not working, I will look them during the doubts part, okay? Just wait, because till now, I have not tested the application whether it's working for me or not, okay?
PAUL: Right now, it's monolithic, not microservice in a way.
PAUL: Okay, alright. Now, let's start checking the routes. Okay, so one by one, whatever the, at least the major 2 to 3 routes that I have, that I will do the testing.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, the health route that I have, let's do a try it out.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Let me just click on Execute, and I can see the status is healthy, okay? So, CTRL-S…
PAUL: Here, I can see the status is healthy, alright, fine.
PAUL: the readiness check with respect to the DB connectivity.
PAUL: Now, generally, okay, it's telling that, okay, now this is also fine in the response body, okay? So, ready that I'm getting.
PAUL: Okay? So, in this case, see, right now, in your case, you guys might not have created any collection.
PAUL: Okay, so yes, I can understand that. So, probably in your case, this particular thing can be blank. In my example, okay, I already have a connection. So, first of all, let's open Quadrant.
PAUL: Okay, in whichever ID you have created it, when I don't remember which ID I have created it, but…
PAUL: Let me just open Quadrant, and let's see.
PAUL: Okay, there is no free cluster here, so I don't think this account… Yes, so… yeah.
PAUL: Because which ID? I forgot?
PAUL: Just to show you in the UI, veteran.tech.
PAUL: Okay, so now this is my…
PAUL: I can say the cluster that I have, the rack class, okay, with this I'm connected, so the credential that I have passed is basically for this particular cluster, okay?
PAUL: Now, this is my endpoint that I have.
PAUL: Okay, my API case, and now if I go to the cluster UI…
PAUL: Okay, you will see that, okay, I have a single collection right now, which is the…
PAUL: documents here, close to, I think.
PAUL: 54, vector points are there.
PAUL: Okay, the configuration of these factors is, like, 1536. Right now, by default, the shardening is 1, segment is 2. Okay. Later on, like, during scaling, you need shards? Not one now.
PAUL: Alright, so I can see, in your case, this collection won't be there. What you can do.
PAUL: to create the collection. Yes, in your case, everybody, it will be zero, don't worry. Right now, I know none of you has created the collection.
PAUL: Okay, so first of all, with respect to creating the collection.
PAUL: Yes, so my initial health checks, those things are passed, so let me just…
PAUL: Switch off all of this, okay? Now, coming to upload and ingest a document. Now, this is the part where you can upload some type of document, okay? So, try it out. From here, you can choose the file.
PAUL: Okay, so you can choose a file, so let me take something with, respect to some document if I have.
PAUL: Okay, so download… some docket file I have with me.
PAUL: 12 vision and keys, Team 2, okay.
PAUL: this document also.
PAUL: Final report, please.
PAUL: Okay, I have taken a sample PDF, you guys can take any PDF, there is no restriction with the PDF selection.
PAUL: Okay, so I've selected one PDF for now.
PAUL: Okay, and I will try to do an execution.
PAUL: Let me see, because the number of data points should increase. Okay, so this 54 should increase now.
PAUL: Okay, so, yes.
PAUL: So right now, can you see that, okay, total chunks created for the document is 27 that I have received?
PAUL: Okay, this was the final name, Team 2 Final Report.
PAUL: Okay, the document IDs… That I have for each of the chunks.
PAUL: Okay, so I can say that, okay, this is done. Probably, if I try to do a reload here…
PAUL: Okay, you can see this number has increased now to 81, so I can say that, yes, successfully, the chunking and the upload mechanism is working.
PAUL: Alright, now this route is working fine.
PAUL: eBay sold… Now, let me, just minimize this part.
PAUL: Because this route is working fine.
PAUL: Somewhere here around, yes.
PAUL: Now, if I go to Documents Info, okay, so this is directly a GET call, nothing I need to pass it.
PAUL: Okay, so here I'm getting, okay, the name of the collection is rack document. Okay, so similarly, in your case, the collection will be created, and in your case, based on the PDF, the number of chunks will be decided. Okay, so status is right now green, so I will say that, yes, this information is working fine.
PAUL: Okay, so documents info. Now, document collection. If you want to delete the entire collection, so that's why in the red, I don't want to delete the collection.
PAUL: Now, coming to asking a question. Okay, so let's try to perform a query operation. Now, this is a post call. So, in the post call, I have to pass it.
PAUL: Okay, so right now, enable evaluation is equal to false, include sources is equal to true, and right now, this is a default question that I have added. Okay, so I don't think, based on the document that I have uploaded.
PAUL: So, really, I need to check the document once, exactly. What is the document that I have passed it.
PAUL: Downloads… technical reports… Okay, there is something with respect to detection accuracy.
PAUL: Okay, great.
PAUL: Let me pass it. What is the detection?
PAUL: some specific question that I'm trying to ask, okay, performance or protection accuracy.
PAUL: We don't set.
PAUL: I'll write a simple query that I have passed it, now let me see, okay, so how much time it works.
PAUL: Okay, so let me try to do an execute, and let's see, like…
PAUL: Alright, it's telling that I don't have enough information about this, but, based on the import that I have taken it.
PAUL: Because I feel that…
PAUL: Somewhere with respect to performance. Really, the document that I've given, I can see the chunking is not really so much good. The chunks are having a lot of information, but really.
PAUL: the processing time evaluation. It means that the API is working fine, okay, with respect to the poor pipeline that I need to check.
PAUL: whether that is… okay, so probably something other in the PDF, if I ask.
PAUL: Let's see whether it works or not.
PAUL: Mmm… Something with respect to…
PAUL: Integration pipelines, let me ask about that.
PAUL: Others, also, please let me know for you the ingestion part is done.
PAUL: Please let me know, guys.
PAUL: That part is done or not. Ingestion for everybody, it is working. Really, right now, the document that I have passed is not so much good.
PAUL: I really like, right now, I have just created the core part. Okay, so based on this document, if I change the document, it might…
PAUL: work. So, what is the… Integration pipeline.
PAUL: Okay, let's see. I'm just trying to check… This one.
PAUL: Okay, I can see the integration pipeline consists of two main components, the image pipeline detection pipeline and the emotion recognition pipeline.
PAUL: So I will say, okay, now for this, particular result.
PAUL: Okay, I am getting… okay, so, like, previously, like, when I passed it here.
PAUL: What is the integration? So, here I'm getting the response, okay, fine.
PAUL: Just a bit. Let me just switch on, the evaluation, this parameter as true.
PAUL: And just be sure, looking into the response, okay, in your response.
PAUL: Because the total processing time was 6307. Okay, now this should increase, because I have enabled evaluation this time. Two metrics only, the faithfulness.
PAUL: and… I can say. The other one is…
PAUL: Answer relevancy, two metrics that I have used for now.
PAUL: This will take time. Evaluation takes time, nothing that we can do. We have to wait.
PAUL: Take something close to $5 to $6 as a snack.
PAUL: Okay, Amit, I know, like, for many of you, I have passed a random thing in my document, so it can happen. Few questions I know it can answer, but really, it depends upon exactly the question. And right now, can you see the response time? Just because I have added evaluation? It really takes a lot of time.
PAUL: So, for the end users, it is not important to actually save this one. Alright, Prathamish, don't worry. I will take care of that.
PAUL: Okay, so really, with respect to evaluation, I feel that have I received any error? Till now, the API response is going ahead. Okay, and if you look here.
PAUL: In the terminal, okay, async query analyzed 4 sources, initializing the RAG evaluator. The RAG evaluator initialized with this one, embedding says, text embedding 3, and right now, this evaluation process, really. Why it is stuck, I'm not sure. But, let's see.
PAUL: Ahmed, I use the original main.py file and app.
PAUL: original main.py, like, what is original?
PAUL: Like, the current version, or which one?
PAUL: No, please go back and check my initial commit. Already I discussed in class on that one.
PAUL: Please go to the initial commit, and please check the content of that.
PAUL: File.
PAUL: No, really, why this is taking so much time, okay? Alright, 50% is done, let's wait.
PAUL: Okay, evaluation is done, I got an HTTP200K. Faithfulness is close to 0.0, and relevancy is 0.88. Alright. Based on the question, really, like, what is the integration pipeline?
PAUL: Okay, the responses that I…
PAUL: add this code, but right now, if you really look into, I have added it in the response. So, right now, the response time is really very, very high.
PAUL: My faithfulness is low, really, low, 0.2.
PAUL: Because this is very, like, generator-specific. Right now, all the evaluation metrics, I have not used any type of retrieval-based metric. These two are directly on top of the LLM that I have done.
PAUL: And generally, like, if you try to ask the same question to some other LLM,
PAUL: Okay, like, directly, integration pipeline, it's very hard, like, a very simple thing that I have asked, like, it can be generic, so I can understand, yes, the faithfulness value can drop here.
PAUL: Now, in this part, I can actually bring some retrieval-based metrics, and based on that, we can increase.
PAUL: the value.
PAUL: But right now, this part is also working fine.
PAUL: No, alright.
PAUL: Please do check out the terminal logs. Whenever you get something, please do check out the terminal logs. It is important.
PAUL: Now, okay, so evaluation and everything is working fine for me.
PAUL: Okay, so let me just close this one. The query part is done. This is your actual route, the endpoint route. Okay.
PAUL: So, whenever you open your main welcome to the RAC US system, the default one without slash docs, you'll be getting this particular information.
PAUL: Okay, now coming to query, okay? So, let's directly perform, like, search for relevant documents without generating an answer. Now, this is the route for the,
PAUL: Part with respect to retrieval, includes hostage crew.
PAUL: Let's pick some other question from the document.
PAUL: Alrighty.
PAUL: One thing with respect to… the system architecture.
PAUL: Alright, let's see whether it works or not.
PAUL: Tell me about the system architecture, in the results, the content that is coming, introduction, use cases.
PAUL: Alright, based on the other content, alright, so these are basically the return.
PAUL: With, respect to… so these are basically the chunks, okay, on… directly, I'm doing a retrieval operation. Here, no LLM has been used. So this route is also working fine.
PAUL: I can say that majorly, the… all the routes that I have, because streaming route, later on, that I will discuss in the next class, but my main route, the query route should work for everyone. The collection… okay, let's try to delete the collection, okay, because really, I've not tried this, but let's try it out.
PAUL: Whether it's getting deleted or not.
PAUL: Let's do an execution.
PAUL: collection deleted successfully, okay? Now, let's see if I try to do a load operation here.
PAUL: Okay? No collection.
PAUL: So, pretty much, blank one.
PAUL: So, yes, whatever thing that I have done, majorly the cleaning stuff is done, so I think this…
PAUL: Part is over.
PAUL: Alright, so majorly, the discussions, I have checked the routes. Everyone, please do check the routes. At any point of time, if you are getting errors, please do check your logs. That is the purpose of using logging. At any point of time, please do check the logs.
PAUL: Okay, based on logs only, you can solve the errors.
PAUL: That's why, at least I feel that
PAUL: We have used, pretty much good, robust, logging mechanism.
PAUL: Alright, now I can start taking some type of questions. How many of you have tested all of the, like, the major routes? Please let me know in the chat. The document upload?
PAUL: The document info, don't use this delete collection. Okay, and after that, try to pass in query. These three routes are important, document upload, document info, and query.
PAUL: Raga says, filling. What is filling, mother, sir? Raga says filling rest is working, trying to fix that.
PAUL: Okay, fine, take your time, that…
PAUL: error embedding content. Just be sure correct API key is there. If there is some issue with respect to your API keys, you simply will get an error.
PAUL: Okay, alright, Rahul, fine, I will come to you, don't worry.
PAUL: Cynthia, collection, recommend, created, fine.
PAUL: Cynthia Manachi, please use the dimension. You are using Gemini, I think. Okay, Gemini, by default, it's 3072 dimensions.
PAUL: And, the, in the initialization of the quadrant vector, we have initialized with 1536, so this is a simple, strict action. Okay, so you need to just figure your embedding dimension correctly, and it should work.
PAUL: Okay, alright.
PAUL: All the requests are working fine. All right, fine. Now let's start taking some questions. It's already 12.39. Okay, so people with doubts, they can raise your hands.
PAUL: So, first of all, Let's go with… Nitesh… Then, Pratamesh… Rajat… Rahul Barihar.
PAUL: Okay, so a few people have unmuted one by one, guys, you can start.
Rajat Khanna: Hi, Paul.
PAUL: Murta, and then… alright, you raise your hand, okay?
PAUL: Google ID.
PAUL: Yes, go ahead.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, I just want to share my screen, it is working, everything is working for me, but, I have one question regarding the billing and cluster part.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PAUL: I have added you to panelists, you can start sharing.
PAUL: Next, Pratamesh, Nitesh, anyone can go ahead.
PAUL: Pratamesh… Nitesh… Rahul… Minted.
PAUL: Yes, Rahul, you go ahead then.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, so Paul, I…
Rahul Parihar: I'm… I'm uploading… I have uploaded, the first rack paper documents, you know, and when I'm trying to…
Rahul Parihar: It had 144 chunks.
Rahul Parihar: Now, I'm trying to see that in the quadrant cluster collection, I'm not able to see that, so… can I share my screen and show you?
Rahul Parihar: And the second is when I'm… when I'm trying to…
PAUL: Once you are added in the panelists, then with the second part, you can proceed.
Rajat Khanna: Paul, I'm, sharing my screen.
PAUL: Yes, yes, I can see your screen.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so…
PAUL: Yeah, now tell me.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so I have, bought the OpenAPI, some, dollars and, using this key, but as I have executed this code, I don't see any API call here where I can see that, because in Gemini, we were able to see the number of API calls and everything.
PAUL: Where only it should come.
Rajat Khanna: As you can see, it's working for me. I have uploaded my own.
PAUL: But you are not getting the OpenAI logs, okay? In OpenAI, it should come. Just wait, let me see from my side. I know it should come. Sometimes it might take some time, just wait.
PAUL: Let me just start sharing my screen. I think this is my desktop 3.
PAUL: Hmm… Open… no.
PAUL: No, this is not that ID.
PAUL: This is…
PAUL: Alright, this is getting loaded.
PAUL: But right now, he has some amount of usage that I have done it today, which is less than $0.1, I feel.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, means I have also done the same. As you can see, I have uploaded the document, and chunks are created.
Rajat Khanna: This one. So you see, chunks are created, and…
PAUL: In your case, everything is showing blank.
PAUL: Really, see, it might take some time to reflect, but I feel that… because, see, the total token usage, if you look into my screen that I am sharing, you will be getting, like, how many total tokens you have taken.
PAUL: It takes time. Sometimes it might take time to refresh. I don't know, but it should not happen for everybody. If you're using OpenAI, you will be getting your entire usage details.
Rajat Khanna: Okay. That's it.
PAUL: So, for others, also, it can be. It's not you. For others, also, it might take time to update this particular dashboard of usage.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, and the other one is that cluster part, where I can see that cluster, in this quadric.
PAUL: scale, let's see, their cluster EVY is written. No, no, no, don't click on scale, yeah, click on cluster EV.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, but it is not routing anywhere.
PAUL: a new tab generally opens. See, pop-up window blocked.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, okay, got it.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, yeah, only these two questions I have. So, later on, I'll just go through code of my own, and as yesterday, you told me to share the resume, and we can get on a call, so I'll share my resume to you, and later on, according to your time, we can have a call.
PAUL: Alright, Vajat.
Rajat Khanna: Thank you.
Prathmesh Atre: Hello, sir?
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Rahul, you start sharing. In the meantime, Murthaza, you go ahead. Yeah.
Rahul Parihar: So, you can see my screen?
PAUL: Yes, I can see.
Rahul Parihar: Okay, so I uploaded, my first question is, I uploaded, the RAG generation model document.
Rahul Parihar: And it kind of made 144 chunk…
Rahul Parihar: data. My question is, over here, you know, when I, search the query, what are different types of RAG implementation?
Rahul Parihar: It gives me an answer.
Rahul Parihar: It gives me a processing time over here, but in the query time, it tells the processing time is zero for all the requests. That's one bug.
PAUL: This is the schema.
PAUL: Have you used Wagger UI previously? This is the schema that I have defined.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, that's why… so why I'm not getting my evaluation as null here? That's my question here, so I should be…
PAUL: Check your terminal logs, check your terminal logs.
Rahul Parihar: Fuck it.
PAUL: really see, even I don't know, I have to check the logs. Without checking the logs, it's very hard for me.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, this is my terminal logs, so…
PAUL: Now, see, here, eval included is equal to false.
PAUL: And you have not enabled the evaluation, show me your parameters.
PAUL: Show me your parameters, go back to FastAPI, Swagger UI, go back to Swagger UI.
PAUL: Go on the top. So here you have… go below, below, below, below, below, below, in the query part, in the query part.
Rahul Parihar: In the Q&A.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, yes, query. You have enabled evaluation, you have kept it false.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, so this has to be true, okay.
PAUL: this, only so many times I told in class I changed the settings also, no?
Rahul Parihar: Okay, my second, okay, so second question is, in the court, okay.
Rahul Parihar: So, quadrant, I'm not able to see collection. Where do I see collections?
PAUL: First of all, click there.
PAUL: Go inside your cluster.
Rahul Parihar: Okay. Then click.
PAUL: Click on, top right corner, Cluster EY. Cluster EY, Cluster EY, yes, click on that.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, okay, okay.
PAUL: It's fine, right now. We'll be talking about multiple databases.
PAUL: Quadrant is my favorite, and Melbours. I started with Quadrant in future…
Rahul Parihar: Right? Like, how many distance cosign and other stuff?
PAUL: Yes.
Rahul Parihar: and evalu… on the usage side, on OpenAPI, I do see a usage here, right?
Rahul Parihar: So…
PAUL: Yes, like, today's usage, till now, in your case, yes, December 14th, I can see some up and down.
Rahul Parihar: Okay.
Rahul Parihar: Got it. Okay, thanks. Thanks.
PAUL: Alright.
Murtuza Saifee: I both.
PAUL: Yes, mortas a mortas fast input.
Murtuza Saifee: Hi, yeah, hi, Paul. Thanks for the, session. It was really good. So, everything is working for me, no issues at all. All the endpoints and everything. So, the one thing which I'm confused is, regarding… so, I checked in the code. This embed query and embed documents, we are not using anywhere, so…
Murtuza Saifee: The embedding is already… we are passing it to access Rector Store, and Langchain takes care of it, right? So…
PAUL: By default, LanChain actually takes care of that. You don't have to do the embedding. During the classes, I told. Otherwise, what happens? Like, in LanChain, within the chain, by default, that feature is there. If you use it, by default, it will call that.
PAUL: Okay, so…
Murtuza Saifee: We don't need to use any, like.
PAUL: No, later on.
Murtuza Saifee: Like, I was insights.
PAUL: No, if you don't use Lancheck, then you need that.
Murtuza Saifee: All right, so this is some… okay, I got that point, so this is probably… so if you are not using Engine, so these are some helper functions that we can use again.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes.
Murtuza Saifee: Okay, okay, thanks. That's… that was my query on me. Thank you.
PAUL: Alright.
Prathmesh Atre: Hi, sir.
PAUL: Yes, Pratamesh.
Prathmesh Atre: Sir, actually, we evaluated based on a few metrics, like faithfulness and all. Is there anything specific, like, related to agentic system or agentic rack? Like, when I went.
PAUL: Yes, there are, like, in DPPL in RSI, there are a few metrics with respect to agent.
PAUL: that part, like, during Langraph, I will talk about that, but yes, there are metrics. In RAGAS, it is not available. You have to change the framework. Probably look into OpenEVAS, PromptBench, there are so many, like, evaluation frameworks, you can look into that. Few of them has that agentic capability.
Prathmesh Atre: I went through DP well, actually, there are a few, like, tool correctness, argument correctness, agent goal evaluation, like those.
PAUL: years.
Prathmesh Atre: Also, sir, like, I have sent you the email, so I just… the question is, like, are you sending any new content else from what we have taken yesterday related.
PAUL: Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
Prathmesh Atre: And, like, what features, is being included in that?
PAUL: I think… exactly, see, even I have not… I have two other notebooks.
PAUL: I think some thing with respect to async processing is there, batch uploading is there, few of those things, like, with respect to optimization, that I feel. What I would request is, like,
Prathmesh Atre: one to two sessions, even at the end of this course, if it's, taken by you, it would be really grateful.
PAUL: Regarding what, like, in Llama Parks, what is your exact requirement? Tell me.
Prathmesh Atre: Okay, I will tell you on the email, let's say. At the end, even if you took that, it would be really fine, and also, like, the other features, like, Llama Index has provided the Lama Parses as one of the features, so other features that they have. If you want to do also you cover, like, even in the single session, if you give the kind of introduction.
Prathmesh Atre: Two to three hours off, then it would be really great.
PAUL: Alright, fine, see, I have the content for that, okay? Now, if you ask me, I will drop, I will share you that particular entire content. That's all. If it's your request, you need to process it, because I will make the content, and I will share it.
PAUL: Now, the idea is, again, to go through the entire class, it means that I need a specific class. So, something like, in the end, we will say totally based on the timelines. Okay?
PAUL: But if you request, I can process that, and later on, if you have any doubts, you can let me know directly in the mail, and based on that, I can let you know.
Prathmesh Atre: That is fine, sir. Like, whatever content that you have already created, you can share it with me, and also I will ping some more if I want. But yes, thanks, thanks for that.
PAUL: Alright, Ratamesh. Next, yes. Nitesh?
Nitesh: Yeah, Paul, actually this Ubicorn is running, but, I can see it is showing unhealthy and 503 service unavailable.
Nitesh: Sure.
PAUL: I have no idea, so start sharing your screen. Other, Mudgesa is there, SM is there, PEG0774 is there.
PAUL: Okay, and everyone, like, Mithesh, you are also there. People with gums.
Mitesh Shah: So, basically, what I'm getting an issue with is, I'm using Google, embeddings, and I'm using the model of embedding 001.
Mitesh Shah: Okay, Gemini, embedding 001. I am initializing it in the embedding.pui, output dimensional 1536. Still, I'm getting the same error that, your, quadrant is 1536, your embedding model is 3072.
PAUL: Alright, fine. Two ways are there, like, one, you change the main one, okay, the quadrate part, other you change the embedding dimension. So, which one you want to.
Mitesh Shah: I tried changing it to Google Generative AI Embedding.
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no, no. I'm asking you, two solutions are there. One is changing your vector DB dimension, okay? The other one is changing the dimension of your, like, the embedding model that you are using, Gemini Embedding 001.
PAUL: But what do you want to do?
Mitesh Shah: embedding model.
PAUL: model you want to change. Alright, fine, then just…
PAUL: I have added you to panelists, okay. Start sharing. Whoever is there in the panelists, please start sharing.
Nitesh: Yeah, yeah, I'm start. I have started.
PAUL: Yes, you know, I've started. Similarly, Mitesh also will start.
PAUL: Hmm, 503 service unavailable, okay? This is me.
Nitesh: I can…
PAUL: Okay, you are using the EY.
PAUL: See, that's why directly using the EY.
PAUL: I was not planning. Anhildeid simply told it me that somewhere it failed, getting address info failed, readiness check failed, readiness check failed means the connection to your vector DB, that has failed.
Nitesh: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, so, see, connecting quadrant client initialized takes embedding 3, embedding small readiness check field. But,
PAUL: Okay, one thing try to do, with respect to the readiness, open the Swagger UI, first of all. Open that slash docs.
PAUL: Slash tops.
PAUL: Open.
PAUL: 8,000 after that in the URL ad slash docs.
Nitesh: Okay.
PAUL: Okay? Go below.
PAUL: Okay, now document upload, click on that.
PAUL: Document upload, pass a PDF.
PAUL: Click on try it out.
PAUL: Pass a PDF?
Nitesh: Any PDF, right?
PAUL: Any PDF for now.
Nitesh: Let me see… introduction… I'm not sure, it should be small, or, like, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Nitesh: It must be in 60 simple documents. This is PDF now.
Nitesh: Hold.
Nitesh: Then it must be in 6, so I think sample reaction must be the…
PAUL: So, sample data folder ones.
Nitesh: Sample the must be over here to see… PDF?
PAUL: These are the other types, I think. EDM, somewhere, so many…
Nitesh: 6th of December, I think you asked me, 13th of December?
Nitesh: Oh, that is why you're appealing.
Nitesh: Stunting.
PAUL: get one, try to do the encryption, okay? Because in readiness check, I have kept at get collection info. Okay, so if there are new collections, because of that, also, it might fail.
Nitesh: Okay, so that… because that is a simple collection. So the idea is that you create one collection.
Nitesh: Okay, yeah, let me have a look.
PAUL: Okay, just pass. In the meantime, Adel can share the screen. Who was there? Yeah, sure. Mitesh, I think. Mitesh, you'll start sharing. Muddha, sir, Peg, you two…
PAUL: People can let me know your problem.
Mitesh Shah: Are you able to see my screen? Matesha?
PAUL: Yes, Mitesh, I can see. Here, it's saying that…
PAUL: Okay, now, exactly like what you have executed.
PAUL: Okay, 3072, okay, got the part. Here you are passing your output, 1536.
PAUL: Alright, here you have passed year 1536.
PAUL: Okay, now… First of all, okay, and show me the initialization of the vector DB. In vector DV,
PAUL: The quadrant collection is configured with 1536.
PAUL: dimension, if you want to recreate. Now, coming to this particular parameter, because sometimes this parameter doesn't work, though you pass that 15 to 26. Just check for an argument in the code.
PAUL: In that particular package. Okay, so where you can pass, that Google Lang Chen, Google Generative BI package, that, whether this argument that you have passed, or by taking a simple test script and add some print statements that, once you have passed.
PAUL: Show me some tests where have you done it.
Mitesh Shah: Stop, I'm exploring this kind of stuff, okay?
PAUL: No, no, no, see, here, where you are printing out the dimension, yes, output dimensionality, okay? Alright. Now, add a, length.
PAUL: Parameter, okay, on top of the result, okay, so that you can count that whatever the vector that is getting created.
Mitesh Shah: Unfortunately, not able to…
PAUL: Because this dimension, I remember, like, output dimensionality, I think this parameter is correct.
PAUL: From Google Import Gen AI. You are using from Google Import Gen AI. The package is different. Please use LandChain Google Generative AI package.
Mitesh Shah: Sorry, bye-bye.
PAUL: Okay, the other thing that you can do, go back, go back, go back.
PAUL: Go to that VectorDV part.
PAUL: Spectra TV.
Mitesh Shah: Victor TV.
PAUL: Okay, embedding dimension here, 1536, change it to 307.
PAUL: Okay? Do a Ctrl-S, close the server.
Mitesh Shah: Already closed.
PAUL: Okay, now, go back to your quadrant UI.
PAUL: The idea is that delete the collection, okay? As simple as that. The server is already closed, quadrant TY, I told, okay? So here, delete it.
PAUL: Okay, now go back, re-execute the server.
Mitesh Shah: No, this is giving me an error.
PAUL: No modulium app, but I think app is there.
PAUL: While it's showing. Like, last time, then how it worked.
Mitesh Shah: It was working.
Mitesh Shah: Got it.
Mitesh Shah: Geo.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: One exception call is there, fine.
Mitesh Shah: Okay, I think I'm just trying it out.
PAUL: No, no, this will work. Try to upload a PDF directly. Let's see what happens.
Mitesh Shah: Just doing something that did be…
Mitesh Shah: I know it's a huge one, but… Stop.
Mitesh Shah: Mango vacuum.
Mitesh Shah: Adding, yeah. It started adding.
PAUL: Okay, there are two things. Change the embedding model or change the vector store. That's the solution. Whichever way you want to go ahead, you can do it.
PAUL: Alright, Mitesh?
Mitesh Shah: out of.
Nitesh: Paul, selected the document.
PAUL: Should I share the screen again?
PAUL: No, no, yes, start sharing and start uploading. If there is error, tell me.
Nitesh: Yeah, there is an error.
PAUL: To show me, show me traction.
Nitesh: nope.
Nitesh: Nope.
PAUL: Gate address info.
PAUL: Oh, goodness.
PAUL: Address info fail, go back to terminal logs. Show me the terminal logs.
PAUL: Alright, after uploading the PDF, we were getting this from upload 500 internet server, created chunks.
PAUL: Okay, now I feel that the issue is there with something vibrant.
PAUL: Okay, cool.
Nitesh: Yeah.
PAUL: Do the other thing in the…
PAUL: EY, vector store Y, go back, go back to your main EY. Okay, check the readiness check once.
PAUL: Because I think the collection is not available, because of that, it is unable to push. At the top, there will be a readiness check, held slash ready here.
PAUL: Yes, try to execute this one.
PAUL: Try it out, click on execute.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: There is some issue. Check the configurations of your, quadrant.
PAUL: If the issue is there, do a re-verification.
PAUL: The issue will die, because here the problem is with that.
PAUL: Vector DB data type field.
Nitesh: Okay, so should I… so you mean I need to, like, make another one? There's…
PAUL: Because I feel the connection is correct, but after that, getting text embedding training, and after your emitting model initialization, because the chunks are getting, but it is not getting connected with the collection. Go to your quadrant device, show me that, whether there is a connection or not.
PAUL: Because that is also important. If there is no collection.
PAUL: Okay, then the problem will come.
PAUL: Polycon Cluster UI.
PAUL: Top right, top right, blue color button, blue color button, yeah, click on that.
PAUL: I feel… I'm feeling that the collection is not there.
PAUL: What happened?
Nitesh: Yeah, I clicked on it.
Nitesh: I'll show those…
PAUL: You clicked on it, but that… this is not the cluster you will. Go back once again.
Nitesh: Oh, yep, this.
PAUL: Okay, because it's in… click on Collections.
PAUL: Because this is referring to the docs, right-hand side collections are there. I think these are tutorials. I think it has not been initialized. Because of that, the collection has not been created.
PAUL: Okay, collections, create collection, click on that.
PAUL: write the name of the collection which was there. I think the name of the collection was rag-documents, or something like that. Even I don't remember, I have to check.
PAUL: I've deleted the collection. What was the name?
Mudassar Hakim: Being uploaded should have populated this, right?
PAUL: during upload?
Mudassar Hakim: I'm sorry, I just jumped in. The upload must have populated this correction, right?
PAUL: No, no, no, no. Like, generally, during the vector service initialization, this collection gets created.
PAUL: Okay, so, like, I feel that the collection didn't got created in his case, because of that, he is getting the error.
PAUL: create a…
Nitesh: acne.
PAUL: In the environment file, in the config file, also the name is written, just wait.
Nitesh: Okay, okay.
PAUL: I'm telling you, it's rag-documents only that I feel, but let me do the verification.
PAUL: It's, rag underscore documents.
Nitesh: Drag underscore notes again.
PAUL: Click on continue.
Nitesh: Global search, e-commerce, Sparta home, I use multi-tenancy then.
PAUL: multi-tenancy.
PAUL: Which payload fold should we leave it? Go for global search, I think it will be much easier with… okay, and single, simple, single embedding.
PAUL: One vector field for it, and choose the dimension here.
PAUL: What is the dimension? 1536, if you're working with that one.
Nitesh: Choose metric, cosine is fine, click on continue.
PAUL: Finish.
PAUL: Okay? Now check.
PAUL: Because this is available.
PAUL: Now go and try to, execute once more, huh?
PAUL: P.
Nitesh: And it's not unique.
PAUL: Because your URL looks good to me. You want to show another quadrant URL, these two things, because your connection is getting initialized. Stop the server and try to start again.
PAUL: In this way, you have to do a little bit of troubleshooting.
PAUL: Here's Modhasar, in the meantime.
PAUL: You can go ahead.
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, yeah, so, today's session was very gratifying, I think a lot of things worked for me, thanks to yesterday's preparation.
Mudassar Hakim: Everything's working fine. It's the next thing which I wanted to.
Mudassar Hakim: do is, I wanted to basically, I normally have this thing in my resume, an icon that clicks and a video runs, explaining about myself. Now I want to basically put an icon over there that runs a small pop-up, like a chatbot, that basically someone wants to interact and understand about me. It can do that, right? So as of now, I can see this application is running, at least for my local.
Mudassar Hakim: The Ask Questions pass is also running.
Mudassar Hakim: I was wondering if I can go directly deploy this to a backend server like a renderer.com. Will it work over there? I know I will figure it out in 2-3 hours, but I thought I'd just take your guidance before I get into all that thing.
PAUL: Yes, see, see, the easiest way is the…
PAUL: create a container, okay, in the next house that I'm going to do, and see, like, wherever you can pass containers. Render, I don't use it, okay? But, like, it's easier at any point of time in any service where you can pull the code. Otherwise, this entire code, you need to move to render. Okay, in Railway, I have done it.
Mudassar Hakim: The RM is also fine.
PAUL: Right?
Mudassar Hakim: I've had some difficulty using Railway.
PAUL: Okay, fine, like, U, Explorer, and I think in render, it is…
PAUL: possible, I think. Okay, I'm thinking about Replit, actually. Okay, sorry, in render, try it out. But I think in render, there are some limits with respect to your image, because when you will be moving that, okay, I think all the requirements that I have.
PAUL: it will be close to 1GB, so you have to check that, what is that limit there, app limit size.
Mudassar Hakim: Because right now it's through quadrant, right? It doesn't matter, right? Even if the size increases. Sorry, I didn't follow this part.
PAUL: No, no, see, that is for vector table. That is separate. I'm talking about the application. This means that in an instance, when you will be installing the requirements, it will also take a lot of space for the packages that you will be installing.
Mudassar Hakim: Correct, correct it does that. I actually have uploaded one project, which is more like a vulnerability assessment.
Mudassar Hakim: So, that is there. I don't know how much space that has taken.
Mudassar Hakim: So you're…
PAUL: Right?
Mudassar Hakim: The space, is what you're calling it out.
PAUL: Yes, because generally, like, back, we used to use Heroku a lot. Heroku is fine, but that app limit size where it fails. Most of the application comes more than 2 to 3 GB.
PAUL: Okay, so test this part. I don't think it will be very huge, because I don't have packages like PyTorch.
PAUL: Or sentence transformers, which takes a lot of space.
Mudassar Hakim: Can you just share… can you let me just share my screen?
Mudassar Hakim: bit more.
Mudassar Hakim: I know I will learn through some mistakes, but if I can quickly fine-tune this right away…
PEG07774: Paul, I'm ready whenever we go off.
PAUL: Do you want to share?
PEG07774: Yes.
PAUL: Okay, alright, I will add you to panelist.
Mudassar Hakim: So, this is my previous, project that I had.
Mudassar Hakim: Okay.
Mudassar Hakim: So that is fine.
PAUL: like, how the integration happened here, like, with GitHub, or,
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, it's GitHub. It's GitHub. So what I normally do is, I create my front-end, I deploy that on many of the available servers to Streamlit, or Streamlit Cloud, and I put my backends in such services, where they can run.
PAUL: So, generally, what happens with these services, you have to, like, how to start the application, like, is there, like, where you pass that particular command.
Mudassar Hakim: So, starting means… these are… so right now, it's on, FAS API, right? So these are all backend.
Mudassar Hakim: My backend services are running, this front-end is unlovable, I've deployed it over there.
PAUL: Okay.
Mudassar Hakim: On backend, basically, it runs, let me just quickly show the… GitHub repo for this.
Mudassar Hakim: So, this is my backend. Yeah, this is my backend.
PAUL: Okay, now see, there the file is in the root folder, main.py. So, like, how render detects your main.py file? That I want to understand, because in our project, our main.py file is within another folder.
Mudassar Hakim: Correct, so it's on the root level. I think that can be sorted. It should not be a challenge.
Mudassar Hakim: It's just a matter of…
PAUL: You can change the imports and you can do that, but how render? Suppose that you have to know that information, because by default, it starts looking for only main.py file
PAUL: That is important.
Mudassar Hakim: Right now, these are the import it is using.
Mudassar Hakim: I don't think this is very heavy, right, as compared to what I'm doing.
PAUL: This is pretty light only, I can say.
Mudassar Hakim: Pretty light, yeah.
Mudassar Hakim: So… so… so concerns coming from your… but again, this is… that's my problem.
PAUL: I have not used Render, if you want, okay, give me time by Saturday, I can tell you.
Mudassar Hakim: That is fine. Render is an example. It's giving me free, that's why. There are other also. Any services where I can deploy it on the backend? I want to go step by step. First step is, I want to deploy this and run and see how it works. Because this is going to be the first time where I have my front-end and backend both packaged in a single, thing.
Mudassar Hakim: Normally, I don't do this. I normally keep it separate, and then I do configurations and authentication and encryption so that everything is fine, but this is something different I'm doing for the first time. That's the reason why I thought I should first check with you, rather than jumping in.
PAUL: Actually, what you can do, like, the same way, you can do it, like, see, use the APIs that we have and integrate in Love Abil. In that way, also, you can do it. Don't use this particular UI.
Mudassar Hakim: Sorry, come again, come again?
PAUL: like, you… It's not necessary to use this EY. You can use your lovable one. You can build…
Mudassar Hakim: What eventually I'm going to do, because this is not the interface I want, I will be making a very nifty interface, which will open like a pop-up.
Mudassar Hakim: Take care. On my resume, and it will start talking. But again, that is secondary. I want to first get this thing running. Is this something I can first go and see? If it's working fine, then I'll start breaking it down and rooming the front end entirely from it.
Mudassar Hakim: You just check, if you… I can directly take this entirely to Render or any other site that you are aware, that will work.
PAUL: I will check. Generally, I think one is a railway render.
Mudassar Hakim: We'll be having…
PAUL: I will check.
Mudassar Hakim: I have tried railway, but I think I had some challenge, that's why I backed out from there.
PAUL: Alright, fine. I will check that part in the next one, because this is a small thing.
PAUL: Thanks.
Mudassar Hakim: Exactly. Exactly. In next class, I will discuss this one. Awesome.
PEG07774: Can I hear my screen?
PAUL: Yes.
PAUL: Please go ahead.
PAUL: And Nitesh, please provide me the updates by doing the verification.
Nitesh: Yeah, actually, I tried it again, but the same issue is there.
PAUL: Okay, fine. Otherwise, just push your entire code to GitHub, okay, and then share. Then, that way, I will try, with my credentials and other stuff, that is the final solution that I can do. So, push your code to GitHub, do a Git in it.
PAUL: And those commands are directly from VS Code also, if your VS Code is connected with GitHub. Try to push it.
PAUL: Don't tell me.
PEG07774: Are you able to see my, opening platform?
PAUL: ESE souvenir, right?
PEG07774: So, Paul, what happened was I ingested one document, and I'm able to see the collection with 65 chunks.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
PEG07774: But when I go to the usage in the platform.openai, I'm not able to see, you know, the calls that are being made.
PAUL: platform.openai docsOvery. Remove docs and slash overview from the URL.
PAUL: Yeah, hit enter.
PAUL: Okay, you are getting redirected into that page, generally it doesn't Apple. Click on your, i, user button.
PAUL: III, where your green color, that signal is there, yes, click on that.
PEG07774: Yep.
PAUL: Boom. Really, like, it is platform.openai for me also, it's the same URL.
PAUL: Okay, I'm just, passing one link in the chat. Just try to open this one, because this should be working fine.
Mudassar Hakim: I think if you go to your accounts, there it shows the usage, that small icon.
PAUL: Let's check your account.
PEG07774: Yeah?
Mudassar Hakim: Yeah, click there.
PAUL: There's no click option only.
PEG07774: No, there's no click here.
PAUL: in the chat, I have shared one link, try to click that link.
Mudassar Hakim: Yours is… okay, I don't know, it's different. For me, it shows the options to go and check.
PAUL: Now, that's why. In some users, I don't know why it is getting redirected. Okay, now it has opened.
PAUL: I have given you the direct URL, so from here you can check.
PEG07774: Okay.
PEG07774: I'm sorry.
PAUL: really, why it was not showing, I have no idea.
PEG07774: Okay, I'm seeing them here. And also, Paul, I'm getting some Langsmith forbidden errors.
PAUL: Okay, because right now, we have not configured Landsmith. No, in today's class, we have not done anything with respect to Landsmith. In the next class, we will be doing the integration.
PEG07774: Okay. And one more thing is, Paul, when you were showing your Visual Studio, you were, you know, the render was HTML. My render is like this, so how, how did you get the HTML render out of this one?
PAUL: And there is an extension, like Markdown Preview. You have to install that extension.
PEG07774: Okay, Markdown Preview?
PAUL: That is a VS Code extension.
PEG07774: Okay. So, Paul, can I ask you one more silly question? That can we take, like, if I take one URL, one endpoint, let's say, document upload, can I follow that endpoint all the way to the code, that exactly how it went?
PEG07774: From here to the exec code that it executed?
PAUL: Yes, you can do that. See, till now, in this class, I'm not told about debugging a little bit. In the next class, then, I will add some breakpoints and show… like, I know many of you, you know are programmers, but for beginners, I think it might be helpful, like, if you.
PEG07774: Well, I'm not able to see how… what ops it goes through to get to that… to get to that.
PAUL: Okay, fine, fine, fine, fine. This part, I will do it. Okay, keep it as a reminder. If I forget in the next class, let me know.
PEG07774: Okay, alright, thank you. Thanks, Paul.
SM: Hi, Bon.
PAUL: Yes.
SM: Yeah, it was a good session today, thanks for that. My, question is, like, today we have written a very simple RAG application.
PAUL: Let's suppose I want to optimize it and improve the performance.
SM: What are the few steps, like, first few steps which I should take?
PAUL: first few steps with respect to C. At every component level, optimization can be done.
PAUL: Okay, now, your optimization, where you are looking for. Tell me which component.
SM: Like, I should get the better responses.
SM: C.
PAUL: Thank you.
PAUL: That will come in Project CC. Till now, I've not added anything. I've not focused on chunking. Right now, the chunking strategy is pretty much… based on the chunks results, it was bad, I think. See, we have to add, like, re-ranking, fusion, ID, a lot of other concepts will come in the next one month.
PAUL: More than one month, I can see. Because in Project 2, like, I saw that many people were asking questions with respect to SQL.
PAUL: Okay, working with structured databases, that part… that part I have included. If you really want, you can go to the GitHub, you can dec… if you can easily decode code.
PAUL: Sleep.
PAUL: For that, I've already shared, I think, in my GitHub.
PAUL: So, somewhere, CTRL-S… If you want, like.
PAUL: all the type of optimizations. Okay, at least I have kept a few, but raise… look into this one. Last class, I told Rahul also. If you want this one, this one is a hybrid. It has dense vector search, sparse vector search, everything is there.
PAUL: So, if you want, you can take this report, okay, for your reference, and you can actually look into the code. I'm going to discuss it probably in the month of February, okay, but
PAUL: like, based on the topics and the implementation, but this is one of the main production RT here, everything, Kubernetes.
PAUL: And the easiest way… can you decode the repose? Please let me know, otherwise I have to tell you.
SM: Yeah, yeah, I can… I can do that.
PAUL: Say, go to my commits.
PAUL: Okay, check each commits. Okay, like, I have phase-wise commits. Phase 1, like AWS, skip this part. Start from phase two. Local development, document processing, advanced chunking, embedding with BG support, dual indexing. Okay, so check this part.
SM: institutions.
PAUL: Okay, check my commits. From those commits, you will get the idea that exactly what I was planning.
PAUL: If any question comes, you can ask me.
PAUL: Got me a meal.
SM: Sure.
PAUL: We'll let you know.
SM: Yeah, thanks, thank you, thanks so much.
PAUL: Okay.
PAUL: Shiva says, Paul, can you please push your code, which has been today's a separate Git?
PAUL: See, my code, if you want… see, if you want my code, you have to look into the first commit.
PAUL: Okay, so look into the first commit of the RAG UA project.
PAUL: I'll go to this one.
PAUL: I won't be creating a separate repo. Go to the commits.
PAUL: Okay, and check the first commit, this one. Code base pushed.
PAUL: Now, here, this is, like, the simplest one where I have the core application. Few other things are there, but this is the actual part.
PAUL: Include.
PAUL: If you want, I can push it, but again, so many pushes in GitHub. That's the thing. Shiba says, okay, so please look into my first commit, the codebase, push to me.
PAUL: This is the actual structure. After that, I added a lot of things.
PAUL: Alright, now… This part is done, I've shared it in the chat. Okay, anybody else? Okay, Naga is there.
PAUL: And Agathpan, yes.
PAUL: Nitesh, please let me know. Okay, Nitesh is not here.
PAUL: Yes, Naga, and Nagapang?
Naga: can I share my screen?
PAUL: Alright, screen sharing remote. Yes, sir, you can proceed.
PAUL: Yes, others, like Nagaphan and Kodalisar, you can do it.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Yeah, hello.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Can you hear me? Thank you so much for all the effort. I just wanted to understand, is there any limitations for uploading the documents? Everything's working fine so far. Okay, is there any limitations in terms of uploading PDF documents or anything?
Nagappan Thanneermalai: For this.
PAUL: Generally, say, by default, I know it's, like, 200MB below that. Okay, if you try to cross that, 200MB limit mark, okay, because right now, I think I have given only one option to document files. Later on, I can process, like, upload multiple files in one shot. So right now, yes, there is a limit.
PAUL: But later on, like, when we work with multi-file limits, then actually I can break it into multiple parts, and then apply batch processing for the uploading.
PAUL: Okay. But right now, this, there is a limit, correct?
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Okay, fine. And, next thing is, how should I see the cost, how much which I used?
PAUL: You can go to the OpenAI, yes, you can go to the OpenAI platform, and then, once you have opened platform.openai.com, so from there, you can check your usage part.
PAUL: Yes, just like right now, I think Naga is sharing his screen. Yeah. Okay, so this is the usage part. From there, you will be getting.
PAUL: Okay, got it. It might take time to load, okay, because I feel that in some cases, as few students have told, okay, readily not available, but you have to be.
Nagappan Thanneermalai: Okay, got it. Okay, thank you so much. Thank you.
Naga: Hey, Paul, I have a question. So… when I'm trying to the…
Naga: See, I gave the keys and everything correct only, but I don't know why it's saying incorrect key provided, so is it supposed to be in a single quote something, you know, the key?
PAUL: No, no, no, no, no quotes.
Naga: But then why?
PAUL: So human.
Naga: It's giving the… I copied, actually, a second key also I created.
Naga: It says incorrect API key provided, and this…
Naga: And then it's asking me to go and check here. So, should I restart, again, the entire application just for the key only, or, like, what is.
PAUL: Same. In these type of cases, when you want a verification, quickly create a test script.
PAUL: Okay, in that test script, hardcode your key, or load it from the ANV, and then test it that your API key is working on.
Naga: Should I, I mean, is it asking for money, or… I don't see that also, like… is it, like, an empty key also? It can take…
PAUL: selling invalid API key, in simple terms. It's told that the… it means that the authentication has failed.
Naga: Well, let me… okay, okay, for example, Raju, 3K, I'm saying.
Naga: Create secret key, okay?
Naga: Okay, so I'm copying this one, okay?
PAUL: Thumb?
Naga: Now I'm going here, I'm going to apply that key here.
PAUL: First, create a test file and check that it is working or not.
Naga: So, like this, right? This one, and then file sale.
Naga: And then…
PAUL: Okay.
Naga: And then reset her.
PAUL: Restart the server, yes, that is the idea, that to restart the server first, but if you have some type of problems, you should always do a validation by creating a test script.
Naga: So, restart server means, like, the… just the app only, or, like, the entire… so, how do I restart the server here?
PAUL: Ctrl-C, close the server. Again, open the server with the same command.
Naga: Same comment, okay, like this, right? Okay.
PAUL: Hmm.
Naga: Share it… I already shared that one, I know.
Naga: So, startup is completed.
Naga: Okay, again, I'm going here.
Naga: Control and Terms.
Naga: Okay, it's opening.
Naga: And now it says… want to browse some file?
Naga: So, we are talking about digital taping.
Naga: Yeah, it's… I don't know why it's always the same problem.
PAUL: No, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, show me the API key.
PAUL: You're saying this API key is wrong? By looking into the API key, I can say it's written all the… generally, all, OpenAI API key starts with SK.
Naga: Yeah, but then why… I given that one, right? So, I don't know why it's taking this one.
Naga: Like, see, this is a key I gave, like, right in front of you. Open MPI key, and then…
PAUL: Yes, we introduced.
Naga: Ian funds?
PAUL: You need to check, this is a .env file, the OpenAI key… okay, have you pressed Ctrl-S after updating this one?
Naga: Yes, it's already.
PAUL: Okay, alright, now, go back to your main.py file.
Naga: Mind.
PAUL: main.py freely file within the app.
Naga: Oh, okay, main dot field, okay,
PAUL: Okay, because here, load.inv is there. Okay, now…
PAUL: One thing you can do…
PAUL: remove that load, underscore .env from there, and bring it under the UV column.
PAUL: This is the other way, because the idea is that the environment variables should be available.
Naga: So…
PAUL: They removed at line number 8.
Naga: Like, never…
PAUL: that, copy that, copy that stuff, and bring it in the UVCon function. Go at the bottom. I think somewhere there will be a UVCon call. At the bottom, scroll directly down.
Naga: Ctrl-X and, okay, bottom, okay.
PAUL: Okay, and now, here, input unicorn, below that, paste it.
Naga: What?
PAUL: Okay? Yes, start the server now, stop and start.
Naga: foot, and then… And Ctrl-C… He wrote a troublesh.
PAUL: Janika, I can start sharing.
PAUL: Colori, sir, you can go ahead, I have unmuted.
Naga: Wait, I'm doing this again.
Naga: It's not the reload process.
Naga: Application set up. Okay, again, I'm doing this, Ctrl and do this.
Naga: Yeah, looks like it is going.
PAUL: Yes, Jenica.
Jainika: Yes, my…
PAUL: I know that.
Jainika: key is not correct.
Jainika: I understand.
PAUL: Okay, fine.
Jainika: And what I understood that there, this has been created, so how to, check whether it has been uploaded or not?
PAUL: The documents.
Jainika: The embeddings are done on.
PAUL: It's telling you a point 0, it means that this is blank, nothing is there in this.
Jainika: Okay.
Jainika: Okay, can we see the document also, or something embeddings also, through any…
PAUL: you will see the document chunk, what is there. Once you click… it is uploaded, you can do the verification.
Jainika: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, if you want, I can, like, I have already deleted that collection, but yes, you will get exactly the total number of chunks and the points.
Jainika: Can I use Olama Local, for the…
PAUL: Now you can use Olama, you can use… see, Olama, it means that later on, when I'll be doing the deployment, then it will become a company.
PAUL: Okay, for now, you can use… I have no restrictions. You can use OLAMA, you have to update, I think, one is your embeddings file, because there you will be using an OLAMA embedding model, and probably in the chain, bad chain, where you will be changing again. So, two files that need to be updated from your site.
Jainika: Okay.
PAUL: Alright, fine.
Naga: Yeah, I'm… I've done that one, but still, it's the same thing. Like, in main NPY, I'm loading in the…
Naga: Unicon? Unicon?
PAUL: So, I'm telling you, first of all, see, for these type of issues, really, you need to fix it by taking a test script. Create a test script, take a simple OpenAI package, try to check whether the API is working or not. These are the simple steps, always, that you need to follow.
PAUL: Because this is nothing like rocket science here. You have to just look into the first part, which is the packages available. In your case, I can see the packages available. Next step, create a test script, just to check that the API is working or not.
PAUL: Then use that particular key.
PAUL: I hope you get my point. Create a test script to check it is working or not, because somehow I feel, in your case, the incorrect API key from where it is coming, because really that ENV file is there, but I feel it's Gemini API key is coming, when I look into your logs.
Naga: Oh, okay.
Naga: So, there might be some reference to some files.
PAUL: Because this is the entry point, main.py, of your application, and in this file, you have very specifically mentioned.
PAUL: Because otherwise, the other way, if nothing is working, I will hardcode everyone, my API.
PAUL: That is the last solution that I have.
PAUL: But I know that…
Naga: Cool.
PAUL: Wherever, like, you need to pass the API key, okay, in the config file, I will hardcode it everywhere, wherever there is the call.
PAUL: Okay, because this is simple Python-related issue, that you need to start troubleshooting from your own site, why it is not working. Because, based on your terminal logs, I can see something other that is coming into the picture.
PAUL: Okay, next, Srinath, Raju, and Hari.
PAUL: Kodali, sir, you have raised your hand, but no response from your side.
Sreenath Raju: Hi, Paul. So I'm getting the same API key error.
Sreenath Raju: And I did tests with, you know, with, that same API key,
Sreenath Raju: How are you okay all right?
Sreenath Raju: Let me share this screen.
Sreenath Raju: Alright, I am adding two panelists. Harihi and Srinath both I have IDD.
Sreenath Raju: Can you hear me?
Sreenath Raju: Yes.
PAUL: Try to create a test script, Naga, and then test it out, as simple.
Naga: Okay.
PAUL: Okay, I'm just hoping you're sharing. Next, I think, Hari, you can start sharing, or Suna, Raju, anyway.
Sreenath Raju: Yeah, I'm sharing my screen. Rejoin.
Sreenath Raju: We'll take the code.
Sreenath Raju: Oh, can you see my screen? Okay, you want to be a panelist, alright?
Sreenath Raju: Because there is no audio from your site. Can you see my screen?
PAUL: Okay, right now, I think Hari has started sharing. Your screen, I cannot see.
Sreenath Raju: I don't know what happened, so… let him finish first then.
PAUL: Yes, honey.
Hari: It is related to debugging of this application. I understand other things are working on my mission.
Sreenath Raju: Just wanted to see, like, how I can place the breakpoints and then, launch this debugger, so that, I can go step by step. So I added a couple of breakpoints, inside the function, I mean, basically inside the files.
Sreenath Raju: I wanted to see, like, individually, how I can debug. I understand somebody asked this question, and then you said.
PAUL: Next class, I will show you this part.
Sreenath Raju: Okay. But, see, you have to look into the main routes, one by one.
Sreenath Raju: Okay, so where you have put, you have sub-put okay?
PAUL: This is the main point, app main, that you have called it.
Hari: Just wanted to see, like, afterwards, in Router also.
Sreenath Raju: president.
PAUL: Yes, from router only, it will go.
Sreenath Raju: Indeed.
Hari: Right, right.
PAUL: That's what…
Hari: Yeah.
Sreenath Raju: your debugger, let me… Yes.
Sreenath Raju: So, start debugging. I wanted to select a JSON file, I… because we are running right now past API, right? I created this launch date JSON with respect to filters. Maybe I'll start once again.
Sreenath Raju: Start debugging.
PAUL: What is the normal Python debugger? What is the problem?
Kodali Purna Chand: Paul, can you hear me?
PAUL: Yes, I can.
Hari: I selected…
PAUL: No module named launch.
Hari: Select me from here.
Sreenath Raju: Why did it fill in?
PAUL: Okay, after UVicon launch, okay…
Sreenath Raju: This Ubicorn is getting this file.
Sreenath Raju: Yes. Why this launch.json app is coming?
Sreenath Raju: Earlier I tried to launch, with, launch JSON, because it's a fast API file.
Hari: So what I have done is…
PAUL: It doesn't matter. See, if it's a Python-based framework, you do… really, I don't work with, like, JSON launches. I directly start my Python debugger.
Sreenath Raju: Oh my gosh.
PAUL: alone.
Sreenath Raju: with Python compilers.
Sreenath Raju: Now, shall I, what is the, like, start debugging?
Sreenath Raju: It is trying to…
PAUL: But AK needs picking up launch.json. Why that is coming?
Sreenath Raju: That is the main problem.
Sreenath Raju: Okay.
Sreenath Raju: So let's stop it and then restart the kernel once again.
Sreenath Raju: There is no kernel, it's not Jupiter, no.
Sreenath Raju: I mean, reopening this Visual Studio. I'm not sure why it is.
Sreenath Raju: Get me in the opener.
Sreenath Raju: Great.
Sreenath Raju: No, Imran, the whole template.py file, actually, it will create a lot of file and folders. Okay, so that's why I told that you can use that one, or manually you can create it.
Sreenath Raju: Okay, so you can test it out, take that file in a blank folder, and you can test it out, the entire project, like, the project structure that I have, the folder structure, it will be created.
Hari: to hear, python file I should select.
PAUL: Me is the main.piFi only, no?
Hari: Started up more.
Hari: It's Saturday, I cannot… Yeah.
PAUL: Python has no module found at risk key.
PAUL: Daniel, for debugging, I don't… love so much of VS Code by Jump, I feel it's better.
Hari: September.
PAUL: VScoded does the job, but… somehow.
PAUL: more details I feel like getting by channel.
PAUL: Okay, so we're here, now let's start it.
PAUL: Okay, creating the environment, installing the packages…
PAUL: Other… in the meantime, yes, Kodalisar, I can see your screen.
Kodali Purna Chand: I just wanted a confirmation that things are working alright, so I've uploaded this document.
PAUL: Okay, 501 chunks, fine, this is fine.
Kodali Purna Chand: This is fine. So then, I've done the query…
Kodali Purna Chand: Yeah, I've changed the question to what suits that particular document, and it has.
Kodali Purna Chand: Sorry?
PAUL: Alright, proceed fine, you have asked a question.
Kodali Purna Chand: And it has given a certain response, so it's all about now validating if the response is accurate, am I right?
PAUL: Yes, because in the parameter, evaluation is equal to null means.
PAUL: During that particular call, in the parameters, you have not enabled the evaluation field.
Kodali Purna Chand: Yeah, that's by purpose.
PAUL: Okay, fine.
Kodali Purna Chand: later, okay? Is there anything else I need to do beyond this? In, because you told three items are important, so I was working…
PAUL: On top of that, go, query is working fine, go on top.
PAUL: That document, the other one, too, is working. The third one was getting collection info, this is also working.
PAUL: Everything is working. 2, 3, and 3 routes are working.
Kodali Purna Chand: Okay, so I just wanted to check one more thing. Right now, we are doing with langchain parsers, right, or document readers.
PAUL: Yes, yes, right now, direct line data loaders that I have passed.
Kodali Purna Chand: So, at some point later, we'll be trying with Docklink or.
PAUL: Yes, yes, in the next project that I'll be discussing, they are at least same. It's only two lines change in the code.
Kodali Purna Chand: Absolutely, yeah.
PAUL: That's why in the next module, I think, for PDF, I might have taken DocLink, for other file type, I might have taken unstructured. In that way, a little bit hybrid that I have done.
Kodali Purna Chand: Alright, okay, okay, thank you. Thanks.
PAUL: Otherwise, in the next class, I will show you this part. Okay, don't worry, test it from your end. If something is there, okay, give me a reminder in the next class, okay, I will show you this entire debugging process first.
Hari: Sure, that works, yeah.
PAUL: Okay, so no more hands are released, alright. Then I think…
PAUL: we are good to conclude today, okay? Now, for everyone, okay, so I know, like, for a few folks who will be there who might have some problems, because
PAUL: This entire thing, we have done it with respect to the core implementation of the RAT. In the next class, it's much more about deployment, that I feel. Containerization, Docker, okay, so those things that we'll be focusing on.
PAUL: So, everybody, please take your time this entire week. You have spent at least 30 minutes, so wherever you feel that you are not comfortable with, okay, use some type of chat GPT, Cloud, anything. Okay, but just be sure that this module is fine.
PAUL: Project 2, the complexity will increase more. Project 3, again, complexity will increase the highest. Then again, in your fourth and fifth project, it will decrease. So, the idea is that you should be good in this.
PAUL: Because modular programming, few people were asking questions in the chat, why not using Jupyter notebooks, okay? So please, for them, it's very, very important so that you guys get the idea of modular coding. This is how everything in production we make it.
PAUL: Okay, so please spend more time. If you're not good in Python, it's fine. Take your time. You have more than one month when we'll be starting our Project 3, and Project 3 will be really a complex one.
PAUL: a lot of modules and a lot of inputs. So, just to be familiar, if you're not good, go and cover a little bit of oops concept, from there you will get the idea.
PAUL: Okay, so spend some time in modular coding, because this is the first time even in class, we have done. My expectation is, many of you know, but I know a few people are not comfortable, so please spend time on this project more running. Then, automatically, Project 2 and Project 3 will be easier.
PAUL: Thank you, got it working, but I must go through the oops. Yes, wherever I have created classes, the constructor, okay, the functions within the classes, at least go through, because majorly the calls happen through that. I'll just create an object of the class, and using that object, everything that I do. Okay, so please go through that, Govinda.
PAUL: Alright guys, so I think, is there a future for AI developers? Yes.
PAUL: It totally depends upon what type of work you are doing, Naga, okay? So, yes, the demands will be there, because everything could not be automated, I can say. It might take more 10 years, but yes. Data engineering is the safest job, I feel.
PAUL: Creating pipelines, and really, like, change your data for data engineers, at least.
PAUL: Alright guys, so let's conclude the session for today. Bye-bye, everyone. Thanks for joining. Let's meet next week.